[Introduction]
[介绍]
DAVID MALAN: This is CS50, Harvard University's introduction
大卫·马兰：这是哈佛大学CS50的介绍
to the intellectual enterprises of computer science
对计算机科学的知识型企业
and the art of programming.
和编程艺术。
My name is David Malan, and if you are among those
我的名字是大卫马兰，如果你是其中之一
in the room who are thinking, why am I in a class of computer science,
在房间里谁在思考，为什么我在一门计算机科学，
realize that I too felt that exact same way.
意识到我也觉得完全一样。
In fact, my freshman year, I didn't quite
事实上，我一年级的时候，我并不完全
get up the nerve to take this class or computer science more generally,
鼓起勇气更普遍地学习这门课程或计算机科学，
and that was largely because I was intimidated by it.
那很大程度上是因为我被它吓倒了。
I was a little nervous.
我有点紧张。
It felt well out of my comfort zone.
我感觉很舒服。
And I really didn't know at the end of the day what it actually was.
而且我在一天结束时真的不知道它究竟是什么。
But realize if you, too, are feeling a little bit of that,
但要意识到，如果你也感受到一点点，
or even if you're among those more comfortable who
或者即使你是那些更舒服的人之一
have dabbled in computer science or programming,
涉足计算机科学或编程，
realize that there's so many blanks that we can fill in along the way
意识到我们可以填写这么多空白
so that ultimately, at the end of the semester, everyone
所以最终，在学期结束时，每个人
will feel themselves on the same page.
会觉得自己在同一页上。
And until then, rest assured that 68% of the people sitting to your left
在那之前，请放心，68％的人坐在你的左边
and to your right and behind and in front
以及你的权利，背后和前方
have never taken a CS course before, which may very well be
从来没有参加过CS课程，这很可能是
the demographic into which you fit.
适合你的人口统计。
But realize, too, that with such an amazing support
但也要意识到这种惊人的支持
structure with so many office hours and sections and materials and beyond,
这么多办公时间，部分和材料以及更远的结构，
realize that what's ultimately important in this course
意识到在这门课程中最重要的是什么
is not so much where you end up relative to your classmates
与你的同学相比，你的最终结果并非如此
in week 10, our final week, but where you end up relative to yourself
在第10周，我们的最后一周，但你最终相对于自己
in week zero.
在零周。
And indeed, that is where we now are.
事实上，这就是我们现在所处的位置。
And as it turns out, computer scientists start counting at zero.
事实证明，计算机科学家从零开始计算。
And so over the next 11 weeks, we will take you
在接下来的11周内，我们将带你去
from being among those less comfortable or perhaps
从那些不太舒服或可能
somewhere in between less comfortable and more
在不太舒适和更多之间的某个地方
to feeling much more comfortable and confident and capable than that.
比那更舒服，更自信，更有能力。
But to get there, we need to understand what computer science really is.
但要实现这一目标，我们需要了解计算机科学究竟是什么。
And this was something I didn't understand until I set foot in a room
在我踏入一个房间之前，这是我不明白的事情
like this.
像这样。
And I dare say we can distill computer science into just this picture.
而且我敢说我们可以将计算机科学提炼成这张照片。
Computer science is about problem solving.
计算机科学是关于解决问题的。
And I know that high school courses typically do kind of paint
而且我知道高中课程通常会做一些油漆
a misleading picture that it's only about
一个误导性的图片，它只是关于
and it's entirely about programming and people with their heads
它完全是关于编程和人们的头脑
down in the computer lab working fairly anti-socially on code,
在计算机实验室工作，在代码上相当反社会
but the reality is it's all about solving problems, and very often,
但实际情况是解决问题，而且经常是
solving problems collaboratively either in person or by leveraging code,
通过亲自或通过利用代码协同解决问题，
programs that others have written in the past.
其他人过去写过的程序。
And what does it mean to solve a problem?
解决问题意味着什么？
Well, you need inputs.
好吧，你需要输入。
So there's a problem you're trying to solve.
所以你正试图解决这个问题。
That is the input.
这是输入。
And you want output.
你想要输出。
You want the solution to that problem.
你想要解决这个问题的方法。
And the sort of secret sauce of computer science
还有一种计算机科学的秘诀
is going to be everything in this proverbial black box
将成为这个众所周知的黑匣子中的一切
in the middle over the next several weeks,
在接下来的几周中间，
where you begin to understand exactly what you can do with that.
在那里你开始明白你可以用它做什么。
But in order to start solving problems, we kind of just
但是为了开始解决问题，我们就是这样
need to decide as a group how we're going to represent these problems
需要作为一个群体来决定我们将如何代表这些问题
and what might a problem be.
什么可能是一个问题。
Well, in this room, there's a whole bunch of people.
嗯，在这个房间里，有很多人。
If we wanted to take attendance or count the number of people in this room,
如果我们想参加或计算这个房间的人数，
I might need to start keeping track of how many people I see.
我可能需要开始跟踪我看到的人数。
But how do I represent the number of people I see?
但是，我如何表示我看到的人数？
Well, I can do it sort of old school and I can just take out a piece of chalk
好吧，我可以做一些旧学校，我可以拿出一支粉笔
or whatnot and say, all right.
好吧，或者说，好吧。
I see 1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
我看到1,2,3,4,5。
I can do little stylistic conventions like that
我可以做那样的小风格惯例
to save space and remind myself.
节省空间，提醒自己。
6, 7, 8, 9, 10, and so forth.
6,7,8,9,10等。
Or I can, of course, just do that on my own hand.
或者，我当然可以自己动手做。
So 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, and so forth.
所以1,2,3,4,5等等。
But obviously, how high can I count on just one hand?
但显然，我可以依靠一方面多高？
So 5 you would think, but that's just because we haven't really
所以5你会想，但那只是因为我们没有真的
thought hard enough about this problem.
对这个问题认真思考。
It turns out that with just these five fingers, let alone these five more,
事实证明，只用这五个手指，更不用说这五个了，
I can actually count rather higher because after all, the system
实际上我可以算得更高，因为毕竟系统
I'm using of hashmarks on the board or just
我正在使用主板上的哈希标记或只是
now with my fingers is just kind of keeping my fingers down and putting
现在用我的手指只是保持我的手指放下并放置
them up to represent ones, really.
他们最多代表那些，真的。
But what if I actually took into account the order of my fingers
但是，如果我真的考虑到我的手指顺序怎么办？
and sort of permuted them, so to speak, so that it's really patterns of fingers
可以这么说，它就是那种置换它们的手指
that represent the number of people in the room,
代表房间里的人数，
and not just the mere presence of a finger going up or down.
而不仅仅是手指上下移动。
In other words, this can remain zero.
换句话说，这可以保持为零。
This could still be one.
这可能仍然是一个。
But what if two is not just this, the obvious?
但是如果两个不仅仅是这个，那么显而易见呢？
But what if it's just this?
但如果就是这样呢？
So raising just one, my second finger.
所以只举一个，我的第二根手指。
What if, then, three is this?
那么，三，这是什么呢？
So we have 0, 1, 2, 3.
所以我们有0,1,2,3。
That's going to lead us to four somewhat offensively.
这将导致我们四人进攻。
But if we begin to jump ahead to five, I might now
但如果我们开始跳到五，我现在可能
permute this finger and this finger up.
将这个手指和这个手指放在一起。
And if I want to now represent six, I could do this.
如果我想现在代表六个，我可以做到这一点。
And now seven.
现在七点。
In other words, I've expressed so many more patterns on my hand already
换句话说，我已经表达了更多的模式
and if we keep doing this, I think I can actually
如果我们继续这样做，我想我其实可以
represent painfully perhaps like 32 different patterns, and therefore
可能代表32种不同的模式，因此也很痛苦
32 different people, on my hands alone.
32个不同的人，独自在我手上。
Or 31 people if I start counting at zero.
如果我从0开始计数，或者31个人。
So what is that-- what's the relationship
那是什么 - 什么是关系
and how did we even get here?
我们怎么到这里来的？
Well, it turns out that computers are kind of simplistic,
好吧，事实证明计算机有点简单，
much like our hands here.
就像我们的手在这里。
At the end of the day, your computer is plugged into the wall
在一天结束时，您的计算机已插入墙上
or it's got a battery, so it either has or it does not have electricity.
或者它有一个电池，所以它有或没有电。
At the end of the day, that is the physical resource
在一天结束时，这是物质资源
that drives these things and our phones and all of technology today.
今天推动这些东西，我们的手机和所有技术。
So if there is either electricity or not, that kind of maps nicely
所以，如果有电或不电，这种地图很好
to no finger or yes finger.
没有手指或是手指。
And indeed, computers, as you probably know, only speak what language?
事实上，你可能知道，计算机只会说什么语言？
What alphabet, so to speak?
什么字母，可以这么说？
Yeah.
是啊。
Binary.
二进制。
Bi meaning two.
毕意二。
And indeed, that refers to the fact that in binary in computers,
事实上，这指的是在计算机中的二进制中，
you only have two digits--
你只有两位数 -
zero and one.
零和一。
We humans, of course, have 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9,
当然，我们人类有0,1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9，
and then we can combine those to count even higher.
然后我们可以将这些结合起来计算得更高。
But computers only have 0, 1, and then that's it.
但是计算机只有0,1，那就是它。
Because at the end of the day, there's actually
因为在一天结束时，确实存在
a direct mapping between power being off and it being a zero or power being on
电源关闭与零电源或电源接通之间的直接映射
and it being one, or some electrons or whatever flowing from your battery
它是一个，或一些电子或从你的电池流出的任何东西
or from the wall.
或从墙上。
So this is why computers tend to speak only binary,
所以这就是为什么计算机往往只说二进制，
because at the end of the day, it just maps really cleanly
因为在一天结束时，它只是干净地映射
to what it is that's powering them in the first place.
首先是为他们提供动力的是什么。
But how is this actually useful?
但这实际上有用吗？
If computers only have zeros and ones, how can they do anything useful?
如果计算机只有0和1，那么他们怎么做有用的东西呢？
Well, think about our human world, where you might have this pattern of symbols.
好吧，想想我们的人类世界，你可能会有这种符号模式。
This is decimal, dec meaning 10 because you have 0 through 9.
这是十进制，dec表示10，因为你有0到9。
And this is, of course, 123.
当然，这是123。
But why?
但为什么？
If you haven't thought about this in quite some time,
如果你在很长一段时间没有想到这个，
this is really just a pattern of three symbols, one and two and three shapes,
这实际上只是一个三个符号的模式，一个，两个和三个形状，
or glyphs, on the screen.
或字形，在屏幕上。
But we humans, ever since grade school, have started ascribing meaning
但是，自从小学毕业以来，我们人类已经开始归于意义
to each of these numbers, right?
对这些数字中的每一个，对吗？
If you think back, this is the ones column, this is the tens column,
如果你回想一下，这就是列，这是十列，
this is the hundreds column, and so forth, and we could keep going.
这是数百列，等等，我们可以继续前进。
And so why does this pattern-- one, two, three-- mean 123?
那么为什么这种模式 - 一，二，三 - 意味着123？
Well, it's because all of us sort of intuitively
嗯，这是因为我们所有人都是直观的
nowadays are just quickly in our head doing 100 times 1 plus 10 times
如今我们正在快速地做100次1加10次
2 plus 1 times 3, which of course gives us 100 plus 20 plus three,
2加1次3，当然给我们100加20加3，
and then the number we know mathematically as 123.
然后我们在数学上知道的数字为123。
But we're all doing this so quickly, you don't really think about this anymore.
但是我们这么快就这么做了，你不再考虑这个了。
Well, computers work fundamentally the same way.
嗯，计算机的工作方式基本相同。
They don't have as many digits--
他们没有那么多的数字 -
0 through 9-- as we do.
0到9--正如我们所做的那样。
They only have zeros and ones.
它们只有零和一个。
And so if they were to store values, you're
因此，如果他们要存储价值，那么你就是
only going to see zeros and ones on the screen,
只会在屏幕上看到零和一个，
but those zeros and ones just mean different things.
但那些零和一个只是意味着不同的东西。
Instead of having a ones place, tens, a hundreds,
而不是一个地方，数十，数百，
they're going to have a ones place, a twos place, a fours place,
他们会有一个地方，一个两个地方，四个地方，
and then eights and 16 and beyond.
然后是八和十六岁以上。
Now, why?
现在，为什么？
Well, one and 10 and 100, turns out those are powers of 10.
嗯，一个，10个和100个，结果是那些是10的幂。
10 to the 0 is technically 1.
10到0在技术上是1。
10 to the 1 is just 10.
10比1只是10。
10 to the 2 is 100.
10到2是100。
And that's why you have ones, tens hundreds, thousands, and so forth.
这就是为什么你有几十，几千，等等。
Computers are apparently using powers of 2.
计算机显然使用2的幂。
Not surprising.
不奇怪。
Binary-- two.
二进制 - 两个。
So if you only have ones, twos, and fours as your placeholders,
所以如果你只有一个，两个和四个作为你的占位符，
if a computer were storing these digits--
如果一台电脑存放这些数字 -
0, 0, 0-- that computer is presumably storing what number so far as we
0,0,0--计算机可能存储的数量到目前为止
humans understand it?
人类明白吗？
Well, that's how a computer would store zero.
嗯，这就是计算机如何存储零。
If a computer is storing literally 0, 0, 0, just
如果一台计算机正在存储0,0,0，只是
like in our human world, that also is 0, but that's technically
就像我们的人类世界一样，那也是0，但这在技术上也是如此
because it's 4 times 0 plus 2 times 0 plus 1 times zero, which is obviously
因为它是4倍0加2倍0加1倍零，这显然是
zero.
零。
Meanwhile, if a computer is actually storing not just,
同时，如果一台电脑实际存放不仅仅是，
say, 0, 0, 0, but instead is storing this value in binary,
比如，0,0,0，而是将此值存储为二进制，
what does that map to in decimal?
这个映射到十进制是什么？
So that's one.
这就是一个。
And now, why, if we change this 0 and 1 to this value here, is this two?
而现在，为什么，如果我们在这里将这个0和1改为这个值，这两个呢？
Well, mathematically, for the exact same reasons.
好吧，数学上，出于完全相同的原因。
And so earlier, I had five fingers, but if you consider just my first three,
所以早些时候，我有五个手指，但如果你只考虑我的前三个，
when I did this holding up one finger, I was representing two.
当我这样举起一根手指时，我代表了两个。
And if I want to represent three, recall that I put up the second finger.
如果我想要代表三个，请记住我把第二个手指放了。
And so the reason that could nicely represent three
因此可以很好地代表三个原因
is because all I was doing with my human hand was counting in binary.
是因为我用我的人手做的所有事情都在用二进制计算。
And I could keep counting more and more and more.
我可以继续数数越来越多。
And so if I have five fingers or five bits, bit meaning binary digits,
所以，如果我有五个手指或五个位，位意味着二进制数字，
I could count up, it turns out, if we do the math,
事实证明，如果我们做数学计算，我可以数数，
as high as 31 by starting to zero.
从零开始高达31。
It's going to be hard to physically do that, but we could.
实际上很难做到这一点，但我们可以做到。
So why is this useful?
那为什么这有用呢？
At the end of the day, a computer, therefore,
在一天结束时，一台电脑，因此，
can represent any number of values from 0 to 1 to 2 to 3 to some number much,
可以表示从0到1到2到3到任意数量的任意数量的值，
much, much higher than that.
远远高于此。
All it needs is enough bits, enough zeros and ones.
它需要的只是足够的比特，足够的零和一些。
Well, what are those bits?
那些比特是什么？
Well, all of us have these days in our phones sources of light, for instance.
好吧，我们所有人现在都在我们的手机光源中，例如。
So I could actually say that this physical device right now--
所以我现在可以说这个物理设备 -
might be a little hard to tell--
可能有点难以说清楚 -
it does have a flashlight and it's technically off at the moment.
它确实有一个手电筒，目前在技术上是关闭的。
But if I turn this flashlight on, thereby using some of the electricity,
但是，如果我打开这个手电筒，从而使用一些电力，
now, I'm storing a one.
现在，我正在存储一个。
And so the phone is on.
所以手机开机了。
Now, it's off.
现在，它已经关闭了。
Now, it's on.
现在，它已经开启了。
And if I see--
如果我看到 -
can I borrow someone's phone real quick?
我可以快速借用某人的电话吗？
May I?
我可以？
OK.
好。
And flashlight.
和手电筒。
How do I turn on the flashlight?
我该如何开启手电筒？
Oh.
哦。
Shake it.
摇一摇。
That's OK.
没关系。
OK.
好。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Oh.
哦。
OK.
好。
So this is great.
所以这很棒。
Now, I can count higher.
现在，我可以数得更高。
Now, this represents the number what if I have two light bulbs or two switches
现在，这代表了如果我有两个灯泡或两个开关的数字
on at the moment?
在此刻？
Yeah.
是啊。
Three.
三。
Because I have a one, I have a one, and I
因为我有一个，我有一个，我
have two, which of course is going to end up equaling three.
有两个，当然最终将达到三个。
And if I pick up a third phone somehow, I could count even higher.
如果我以某种方式拿起第三部手机，我可能算得更高。
Technically, if I had three light bulbs on--
从技术上讲，如果我有三个灯泡 -
one, one, one-- what would that value be?
一，一，一 - 这个价值是多少？
Seven.
七。
Because it's a four plus a two plus a one, and so forth.
因为它是四加一加二加一，等等。
Thank you so much for the spontaneity.
非常感谢您的自发性。
So why does this not lead to limitations for us?
那为什么这不会对我们造成限制呢？
I can count in decimal as high as I want.
我可以按照我想要的十进制计算。
I can now count in binary as high as I want, so long as I have enough bits.
我现在可以用我想要的二进制数来计算，只要我有足够的位数。
But how do I actually represent other information?
但是，我如何实际代表其他信息呢？
Well, if I want to represent something like a letter, how do I get there?
好吧，如果我想代表一个类似字母的东西，我该如何到达那里？
If computers only have electricity in them and they use binary to count,
如果计算机中只有电，并且他们使用二进制计数，
and yet somehow they're much more useful than just doing math--
然而不知何故，它们比仅仅做数学更有用 -
they can have text messages and e-mails and websites and videos and more--
他们可以收到短信和电子邮件，网站和视频等 -
how do we get from zeros and ones to letters?
我们如何从零和一到字母？
Well, we-- yeah.
好吧，我们 - 是的。
Sorry.
抱歉。
A little louder.
有点大声。
Yeah.
是啊。
We just need to kind of relate the numbers to letters.
我们只需要将数字与字母联系起来。
In other words, all the people in this room just need to decide at some point
换句话说，这个房间里的所有人都需要在某个时候做出决定
that, you know what?
那，你知道吗？
If we want to represent something like the capital letter A,
如果我们想要代表大写字母A，
we just need to decide on a pattern of bits,
我们只需要决定一个比特模式，
a pattern of fingers, that's going to represent A.
手指的图案，这将代表A.
And it turns out humans years ago just unilaterally
几年前，人类只是单方面地证明了这一点
decided 65 shall be the decimal number that represents capital letter A.
决定65应为代表大写字母A的十进制数。
And you might guess capital B is represented by what decimal number?
您可能猜测大写字母B由十进制数表示？
66.
66。
And then C is 67 and so forth.
然后C是67，依此类推。
And there's a mapping of like 128 or even 256 possible values
并且有一个类似128或甚至256个可能值的映射
for all the keys you might see on a typical keyboard
对于您在典型键盘上可能看到的所有按键
in order to represent letters.
为了代表信件。
Now, how does a computer distinguish, though, numbers from letters?
现在，计算机如何区分来自字母的数字？
Well, just depends on the context.
嗯，只取决于上下文。
If you're using like a calculator program on your Mac
如果你在Mac上使用像计算器程序一样
or PC or iPhone or Android, well, the computer, the device,
或PC或iPhone或Android，以及计算机，设备，
is just going to know contextually, let me interpret this pattern of zeros
我只是要了解上下文，让我解释这种零模式
and ones as actual numbers to do math.
和一些作为数学的实际数字。
But if you're using the SMS app or the messages app on your phone,
但是，如果您在手机上使用短信应用或短信应用，
you're going to actually be in the context of text,
你真的会在文本的背景下，
and so your phone is going to interpret that same pattern of zeros and ones,
所以你的手机将解释相同的零和一个模式，
or light bulbs being off, or, at the end of the day, transistors,
或灯泡关闭，或在一天结束时，晶体管，
tiny pieces of hardware and computers that are either on or off--
无论是开还是关的小件硬件和电脑 -
it's going to interpret those patterns as just representing a letter.
它会将这些模式解释为只是代表一个字母。
If you're in the context of a text messaging application or Microsoft Word
如果您在文本消息应用程序或Microsoft Word的上下文中
or Google Docs or the like, it completely depends on context.
或Google Docs等，它完全取决于上下文。
The system we humans came up with just called ASCII, American Standard Code
我们人类想出的系统叫做ASCII，美国标准代码
for Information Interchange.
用于信息交换。
The name isn't interesting, but the fact that we all agreed years ago
这个名字并不有趣，但事实是我们几年前都同意了
that 65 is A and so forth is what's important.
65是A等等是重要的。
And so for instance, if we look at this mapping here
例如，如果我们在这里查看此映射
of just the first few letters, what does this mean?
只是前几个字母，这是什么意思？
If I were to now get a text message and I had the ability somehow
如果我现在要收到短信，我就有了这种能力
to look underneath the hood, so to speak, at the pattern of zeros and ones
可以这么说，看看引擎盖下面是零和一个模式
that someone had just texted me, and that pattern,
有人刚发短信给我，那个模式，
if I convert it to decimal, technically said, let's say, 72 and 73--
如果我把它转换成十进制，技术上说，让我们说，72和73--
so I get a whole bunch of zeros and ones.
所以我得到了一大堆零和一些。
I do some math and I realize, OK, I just received 72 and 73,
我做了一些数学计算，我意识到，好吧，我刚收到72和73，
but this is texting, and so it's not just numbers my friend is sending me.
但这是短信，所以这不仅仅是我朋友寄给我的数字。
It's a message.
这是一条消息。
What message did my friend likely send me if he or she sent 72 and then 73?
如果他或她发送72然后发送73，我的朋友可能发送了什么消息？
Yeah.
是啊。
Hi.
你好。
H-I. Because if you skim ahead at the right there,
HI。因为如果你在那里向前撇去，
that just happens to be in ASCII the mapping between 72 and 73, H and I.
恰好是在ASCII中72和73，H和I之间的映射。
If technically, the message had a third byte, if you will.
从技术上讲，如果你愿意的话，消息有第三个字节。
A byte, if you've ever wondered, is just eight bits.
如果你想知道的话，一个字节只有8位。
It's convenient to talk not in terms of single bits,
不用单比特来说话很方便，
where you can't count very high, but with a byte, or eight bits,
你不能计算很高，但有一个字节，或八位，
you can count higher.
你可以算得更高。
And so it turns out if I received a third byte, another sequence of eight
事实证明，如果我收到第三个字节，另一个是八个字节
zeros and ones together--
零和一起 -
33.
33。
How would we know what this message now is?
我们怎么知道现在这个消息是什么？
Yeah.
是啊。
So it turns out you would not know this other
事实证明你不会知道另一个
than by guessing or Googling or just coming in with this knowledge.
而不是通过猜测或谷歌搜索或只是进入这种知识。
This is now "HI!"
现在是“HI！”
with an exclamation point because 33 just so happens, if you look it up,
带着感叹号，因为33就是这样，如果你查一查，
to map to an exclamation point, as well.
也要映射到感叹号。
Now, if we actually looked at the binary of this,
现在，如果我们真的看了这个的二进制，
you would actually see this pattern of zeros and ones.
你会真正看到这种零和一种模式。
This is how you represent 72 in binary.
这就是你用二进制表示72的方法。
This is you represent 73.
这是你代表73。
And this is how you represent 33.
这就是你如何代表33。
And notice I've only used one, two, three, four, five, six bits,
请注意我只使用了一个，两个，三个，四个，五个，六个位，
even though I technically tend to receive things in units of 8,
即使我在技术上倾向于以8为单位接收东西，
units of bytes.
单位字节。
But why did I not bother writing another 00 here and another 0 here?
但是为什么我不打扰在这里写另一个00和另一个0呢？
Does it matter when you write these things out?
你写这些东西的时候有用吗？
No.
没有。
Not really.
并不是的。
Like in English, in our human world, if you were to write one, two, three,
就像在英语中一样，在我们的人类世界中，如果你要写一，二，三，
that's 123.
那是123。
If you were to write 0, 1, 2, 3, that's still 123.
如果你要写0,1,2,3，那仍然是123。
So even though we tend to get them in clusters of 8,
所以即使我们倾向于将它们分成8个簇，
we don't necessarily need to write those when just talking about them.
我们不一定要在谈论它们时写出那些。
So what have we done?
那我们做了什么？
Well, let me introduce a fancier word now known as abstraction.
好吧，让我介绍一个现在称为抽象的更高档的词。
Abstraction is just a term generally used in computer science and we'll soon
抽象只是计算机科学中常用的术语，我们很快就会出现
see in programming for taking some low level-- like literally low level--
在程序设计中看到一些低级别 - 比如字面上的低级别 -
implementation details, like minutiae even, and understanding them
实现细节，甚至是细节，并理解它们
at some point, but then deciding this is not a useful level conceptually
在某些时候，但在概念上决定这不是一个有用的水平
to think about problems.
思考问题。
I really don't want to solve problems in this world of thinking in 0's and 1's.
我真的不想在0和1的思维世界中解决问题。
I'd much rather think about things minimally in decimal, or better yet,
我更倾向于用十进制来考虑最小的东西，或者更好的是，
in the context of letters if I'm actually receiving text, or even
如果我实际上是在接收文本，甚至是
some other representation.
其他一些代表。
So abstraction is about taking fairly low level details
所以抽象是关于采用相当低级别的细节
and just simplifying them so that we can have a more useful conversation
并简化它们，以便我们可以进行更有用的对话
and never again worry about where the electricity is coming from.
再也不用担心电力的来源了。
We can just stipulate my computer can represent zeros and ones.
我们可以只规定我的电脑可以代表0和1。
Therefore, it can represent numbers.
因此，它可以代表数字。
Therefore, it can also represent ASCII or letters.
因此，它也可以表示ASCII或字母。
And we can kind of move on and start solving more interesting problems.
我们可以继续前进并开始解决更多有趣的问题。
But it would seem that we can't solve all problems because on my keyboard
但似乎我们无法解决所有问题，因为在我的键盘上
here, this American keyboard here, there's a whole bunch of symbols,
在这里，这个美国键盘在这里，有一大堆符号，
like a 100 or 200 maybe in total if we actually hit shift and option and all
如果我们实际上击中了班次和选项，那么总共可能是100或200
of that.
那个。
But what you don't see are some pretty common characters.
但你看不到的是一些非常常见的角色。
Especially in a very international audience,
特别是在非常国际的观众中，
what can I apparently not even type on this keyboard?
我甚至不能在这个键盘上键入什么？
What kinds of symbols?
什么样的符号？
Yeah.
是啊。
Anything with an accent.
任何带有重音的东西。
If you have accents over vowels or other letters.
如果你有元音或其他字母的重音。
What else?
还有什么？
I'm sorry.
对不起。
Umlauts or other characters above letters.
变音字母或字母上方的其他字符。
Yeah.
是啊。
Like pound symbol?
像英镑符号？
Oh.
哦。
Like the UK pound symbol.
像英国英镑符号。
Sure.
当然。
And other countries, too.
和其他国家一样。
Any number of Asian languages.
任意数量的亚洲语言。
There's so many symbols that are not depicted on this keyboard,
这个键盘上没有描绘太多符号，
and yet somehow, all of us with international keyboards or phones
但不知何故，我们所有人都使用国际键盘或手机
can surely express themselves.
可以肯定地表达自己。
But that's because phones and computers these days don't just use ASCII.
但那是因为现在手机和电脑不只是使用ASCII。
ASCII literally used just eight bits total.
ASCII字面上总共使用了8位。
Technically seven, but then, ultimately, really eight.
技术上七，但最终，真的八。
And with eight bits, if you actually do the math--
有八位，如果你真的做数学 -
if you have eight bits or eight fingers, you
如果你有八位或八指，你
can only permute them in 256 total possible ways, which
只能以256种可能的方式对它们进行置换
is to say that you can only represent 256 characters using ASCII with numbers
是说您只能使用带数字的ASCII表示256个字符
underneath the hood, and that's not enough to represent
在引擎盖下面，这还不足以代表
so many different symbols like those enumerated here.
许多不同的符号，如这里列举的那些。
You can't represent any of the accents that you can nonetheless
尽管如此，您无法代表任何口音
type on your Macs and PCs and you certainly
您可以在Mac和PC上输入
can't type these things, which are very much in vogue.
不能输入这些非常流行的东西。
Which even though they're pictures, they're actually just characters.
即使它们是图片，它们实际上只是人物。
Because it turns out some years ago, the world decided eight bits is not enough.
因为事实证明，几年前世界决定八位是不够的。
Let's start using something called Unicode, where you actually use
让我们开始使用你实际使用的名为Unicode的东西
one or two or three or even four bytes.
一个或两个，三个甚至四个字节。
So eight bits or 16 bits, 24 bits, or even 32 bits to represent characters.
所以八位或16位，24位，甚至32位来表示字符。
And now, we have the ability to represent thousands or even
现在，我们有能力代表成千上万甚至是
millions of characters.
数百万字符。
And frankly, daresay, the result of that huge amount of availability
坦率地说，daresay，这是大量可用性的结果
is partly why there are so many of these things these days.
这就是为什么现在有这么多东西的原因。
And they just keep making more because there's just so many different numbers
他们只是继续做更多，因为有这么多不同的数字
available to us.
我们可以使用。
So Unicode is often a specific version of it called UTF-8,
所以Unicode通常是它的特定版本，称为UTF-8，
which we'll see before long.
我们不久就会看到它。
But let me ask this question here.
但是，让我在这里提出这个问题。
This is a crying face with joy, I think this is called.
这是一个充满欢乐的哭泣的脸，我想这就是所谓的。
So it turns out, according to Apple or iOS,
事实证明，根据Apple或iOS，
this is the most popular emoji that at least iPhone people
这是至少iPhone人最流行的表情符号
are sending to each other.
正在互相发送。
So when you're receiving this, though, if we can really take the fun out
所以，当你收到这个时，如果我们能真正把它带出去的话
of this, what pattern of bits are you actually receiving from your friend?
对此，您实际从朋友那里得到了什么样的位？
He or she is clearly trying to express some emotion,
他或她显然想表达一些情感，
but really, what your friend is sending you-- the decimal number 128,514.
但实际上，你朋友送你的是什么 - 十进制数128,514。
Or really, if you looked at the zeros and ones coming
或者真的，如果你看看零和即将到来的
to you over the internet or airwaves, you're
通过互联网或电波给你，你
getting this pattern of zeros and ones, which is hardly joyful or hardly
得到这种零和一种模式，这很难或很难
descriptive, but all your phone or computer
描述性的，但所有的手机或电脑
are doing is seeing this pattern of bits,
正在做的是看到这种位模式，
looking it up in like a little cheat sheet, and saying, oh.
哦，像一个小的备忘单，查找它，然后说，哦。
Whenever I see this pattern of bits in the context of text like texting,
每当我在发短信等文本的上下文中看到这种位模式时，
I should actually display it as that picture.
我应该把它显示为那张照片。
Now, that picture has a lot of yellow and other colors
现在，那张照片有很多黄色和其他颜色
in it, but how do we even get there?
在它，但我们怎么去那里？
Well, it turns out that this same pattern of numbers--
好吧，事实证明，这种数字模式 -
72, 73, 33-- which just to be sure, a moment ago, meant what?
72,73,33--刚才可以肯定，那意味着什么？
Hi.
你好。
In the context of a textual program like Microsoft Word, Google Docs, texting,
在诸如Microsoft Word，Google Docs，短信等文本程序的上下文中，
this means hi.
这意味着你好。
But what if you saw this same pattern of bytes--
但是，如果你看到相同的字节模式 -
and again, we could draw the zeros and ones,
再一次，我们可以绘制零和一，
but it's not interesting anymore, so we're going
但它不再有趣了，所以我们要走了
to abstract away at the decimal level.
抽象小数级别。
If you got this same pattern of zeros and ones
如果你有相同的零和一个模式
or numbers in the context of like Photoshop or a browser
或类似Photoshop或浏览器的上下文中的数字
or some kind of photo program, well, it might make more sense
或某种照片程序，好吧，它可能更有意义
to interpret it not as text, but as imagery, some kind of colors.
把它解释为文本，而不是图像，某种颜色。
Well, it turns out there's this other system in the world--
好吧，事实证明世界上还有另一个系统 -
you might have seen this acronym before--
你可能以前见过这个缩写词 -
called RGB-- red, green, blue.
称为RGB--红色，绿色，蓝色。
And this is just a way of humans having standardized years
这只是人类标准化岁月的一种方式
ago that you know what?
以前你知道吗？
If we want to represent a dot on someone's screen, otherwise known
如果我们想在某人的屏幕上表示一个点，否则就知道了
as a pixel a tiny little square on the screen
作为一个像素，屏幕上的一个小方块
of your phone, your laptop, or even TV these days,
这些天你的手机，笔记本电脑，甚至是电视，
we're going to use three bytes--
我们将使用三个字节 -
one byte to specify how much red should be in that specific pixel,
一个字节，用于指定该特定像素中应有多少红色，
one more byte to specify how much green should be combined with red to form
再多一个字节来指定绿色应与红色组合多少才能形成
that pixel, and then one more byte, a third,
那个像素，再一个字节，第三个，
to represent how much blue to combine with those other two colors
表示与其他两种颜色结合的蓝色多少
to make a new color all together.
一起做一个新的颜色。
So it's kind of like combining paints, except in this case,
所以它有点像组合涂料，除了在这种情况下，
it's more really waves of light in order to get a specific color using just
为了获得特定的颜色，它更像是一波光
red, green, and blue as your palette.
红色，绿色和蓝色作为您的调色板。
And so if we were to see this red, green, blue pattern and say,
所以，如果我们看到这种红色，绿色，蓝色的图案，并说，
you know what?
你知道吗？
Give me 72 red, 73 of green, and 33 of blue.
给我72红色，73绿色，33蓝色。
If the total possible range that I alluded to earlier is like 0 to 256,
如果我之前提到的总可能范围是0到256，
or technically 0 to 255 if you start counting in computer science from zero,
如果从零开始计算机科学计数，或技术上0到255，
this is like a medium amount of red, medium amount of green,
这就像中等量的红色，中等量的绿色，
and just a little bit of blue, if the range goes from 0 to 255.
如果范围从0到255，则只需要一点点蓝色。
So if you combine these three things together
所以，如果你把这三件事结合起来
and you want to know what color you get--
你想知道你得到什么颜色 -
yeah.
是的。
So it's kind of a light yellow that looks like this.
所以它看起来像是一种淡黄色。
So if a computer is storing a single dot on the screen that
因此，如果计算机在屏幕上存储单个点
happens to be in yellow, what the computer's actually storing
恰好是黄色，计算机实际存储的是什么
is not this dot physically, but a pattern of three
这不是物理上的点，而是三点的模式
bytes-- how much red, how much green, how much blue should the computer
字节 - 计算机应该多少红，多少绿，多少蓝
display at this particular point.
在这个特定的点上显示。
So if we look at this crying face of joy and we kind of enhance or zoom in
因此，如果我们看到这种欢乐的哭泣面孔，我们会增强或放大
on it here, you can actually see it start to pixelate, so to speak,
在这里，你可以看到它开始像素化，可以这么说，
where you start to see the dots.
你开始看到点的地方。
If I punch in a little more, now you can really
如果我再多一点，现在你真的可以
start to see the dots on the screen.
开始看到屏幕上的点。
And if I go an even further, you can actually
如果我走得更远，你实际上可以
see the tiny little squares that compose this image, most of which
看到组成这个图像的小小方块，其中大部分都是
at the zoom level are yellow, but a bunch of which are black,
在缩放级别是黄色，但一堆是黑色，
a bunch of which are light black or dark yellow.
一堆是浅黑色或深黄色。
And that's what composes this image ultimately.
这就是最终构成这个形象的原因。
So this is to say if you count up all of the pixels on the screen
所以这就是说你是否计算了屏幕上的所有像素
and then multiply it by one, two, three bytes, that's
然后将它乘以一，二，三个字节，即
how many bytes or kilobytes or megabytes, if you've heard those terms,
如果您听过这些条款，那么多少字节或千字节或兆字节，
are going to be stored on your computer just to represent an image.
将被存储在您的计算机上只是为了表示图像。
So we've gone from electricity to down here, so to speak, to zeros and ones,
所以我们已经从电力转到了这里，可以说是零和一个，
to decimal, now to colors.
到十进制，现在到颜色。
Well, with colors, you can get images.
嗯，有了颜色，你可以得到图像。
What comes after images?
什么后图像？
Well, we've all watched videos or movies certainly digitally these days.
好吧，我们这些天都以数字方式观看了视频或电影。
Well, what is a movie or a video file?
那么，什么是电影或视频文件？
How might that be implemented?
怎么可能实现？
Say it a little louder.
说得有点大声。
Yeah.
是啊。
It's a collection of images.
这是一组图像。
If you've ever heard of frames per second--
如果你曾经听说过每秒帧数 -
like movies tend to be 24 frames per second or 30 frames per second--
像电影往往是每秒24帧或每秒30帧 -
that just means that a typical movie, every second
这只是意味着一部典型的电影，每一秒
is showing you 24 or 30 images per second
每秒显示24或30张图像
and they're just flying by so quickly that you actually
他们实际上飞得太快了
don't notice you're just watching a sequence of static images.
不要注意到你只是在观看一系列静态图像。
It's like as a kid, if you ever had one of those paper flip books where there's
就像小时候一样，如果你曾经有过那些纸质翻书的话
tons of drawings in them, and as you flip through the pages,
大量的图纸，当你翻阅页面时，
you see things moving, but that's just because your eyes are just
你看东西在移动，但那只是因为你的眼睛是公正的
seeing little snapshots ever so quickly of something moving on the paper.
看到一些快照在纸上移动的东西很快。
That's all a video file actually is.
这实际上是一个视频文件。
So if you have an iPhone and you've ever played with these animojis,
所以如果你有一部iPhone并且你曾经玩过这些animojis，
so to speak, well, all those are are little video files
可以这么说，所有这些都是小视频文件
composed of lots and lots and lots of images
由很多很多图像组成
that you have saved on your phone or texted to someone else.
您已保存在手机上或发送给其他人的短信。
And if we just think, now, we're at the point of video, but that's OK.
如果我们只是想，现在，我们正处于视频点，但那没关系。
Videos are just bunches of images.
视频只是一堆图像。
Images are just bunches of colors.
图像只是一堆颜色。
Colors are just patterns of bits.
颜色只是比特模式。
And bits, at the end of the day, are just
在一天结束时，比特只是
the result of electricity coming into my machine or transistors
电流进入我的机器或晶体管的结果
turning switches on and off.
打开和关闭开关。
Like we've all of a sudden to hold this entire story, but none of us
就像我们突然想要掌握这整个故事一样，但我们都没有
ever is going to need to really think about binary in the context of videos
曾经需要在视频环境中真正考虑二进制
because a video is just an abstraction on top of bunches of images,
因为视频只是一堆图像的抽象，
and images are just an abstraction on top bunches of pixels, and so forth.
和图像只是顶部像素束的抽象，依此类推。
So we can keep painting this hierarchy that
所以我们可以继续绘制这种层次结构
just allows us to talk about things at a more useful level,
只是让我们在更有用的层面上讨论事情，
and the reason we had this conversation is
我们进行这次谈话的原因是
just because we needed a way to represent
只是因为我们需要一种表达方式
inputs and outputs to problems.
输入和输出问题。
Let me pause there for just a second to see if there's any questions.
让我暂停一下，看看是否有任何问题。
Anything at all?
什么都没有？
No?
没有？
All right.
行。
So what's inside this black box?
那黑盒子里面有什么？
Well, it turns out this is where the really interesting work starts
嗯，事实证明这是真正有趣的工作开始的地方
to happen and the thought starts to come in.
发生了，思想开始进入。
This is the proverbial algorithms, step by step instructions
这是众所周知的算法，一步一步的指示
for solving some problem.
解决一些问题。
And some of you might have solved this problem before,
你们中的一些人之前可能已经解决了这个问题，
either digitally or textually, but of course,
无论是数字还是文字，但当然，
if you have contacts in your phone these days
如果你这些天手机里有联系人
and you've got bunches of friends and family,
你有很多朋友和家人，
odds are they're alphabetized by first name or last name.
可能性是按名字或姓氏按字母顺序排列。
And you have auto complete these days, but it really is just
这些天你已经自动完成了，但它确实是公正的
a long list of names and numbers.
一长串的名字和数字。
That's not all that different from yesteryear's implementation
这与昔日的实施并没有什么不同
of the same problem, which was this device here, a phonebook.
同样的问题，这个设备在这里，一个电话簿。
Now, this phonebook might have a friend of ours in it, say Mike Smith,
迈克史密斯说，现在，这本电话簿上可能有我们的朋友。
whose last name starts with S. And I could, of course,
其姓氏以S开头。当然，我可以
if trying to find Mike Smith, start by looking
如果想找到迈克史密斯，首先要看
at the first page, the second page, the third page, the fourth page,
在第一页，第二页，第三页，第四页，
and eventually, just hopefully find Mike Smith.
最终，希望找到迈克史密斯。
Indeed, is this algorithm, this step by step process,
的确，就是这个算法，这个一步一步的过程，
correct for finding someone like Mike Smith?
找到像迈克史密斯这样的人是对的？
Yeah.
是啊。
It's correct.
这是正确的。
It's stupid and slow perhaps because it's
它的愚蠢和缓慢也许是因为它
going to take forever in a phone book of this size,
要把这个大小的电话簿永远拿走，
but it is correct because if Mike's in here, I will, in fact, find him.
但这是正确的，因为如果迈克在这里，我实际上会找到他。
But I could do this better.
但我可以做得更好。
I could do it sort of two at a time.
我一次可以做两件事。
So two, four, six, eight, 10-- or imperfectly--
所以两个，四个，六个，八个，十个或不完美 -
10, 12, 14.
10,12,14。
Is that faster?
那更快吗？
Obviously, it's going twice as fast.
显然，它的速度是原来的两倍。
Is it correct?
这是对的吗？
No.
没有。
Why is it not correct?
为什么不正确？
Yeah.
是啊。
I might miss him, right?
我可能会想他，对吗？
Mike just accidentally might eventually get sandwiched between two pages
迈克偶然可能最终夹在两页之间
and I have the unlucky experience of just missing him.
我有一个不幸的经历，只是想念他。
Now, is it fixable?
现在，它可以修复吗？
Yeah.
是啊。
I can probably, once I hit like SN or the T section, for instance--
我可能，一旦我像SN或T部分一样，例如 -
I can just say, obviously, I've gone too far for Mike.
我可以说，显然，我为迈克走得太远了。
Let me just double back one or just a few pages.
让我只翻回一页或几页。
So it is fixable.
所以它是可以修复的。
And so long as I've saved time by flying through this twice as fast,
只要我通过快速飞过这两倍节省时间，
can I at least afford to spend a few more steps at the very end just
我至少可以在最后花费更多的步骤
to find Mike Smith?
找到迈克史密斯？
But none of us are going to do that.
但我们都不会那样做。
And our Apple devices and Android devices certainly
我们的Apple设备和Android设备肯定
don't do that for efficiency today.
今天不要为了效率而这样做。
Odds are most of us are going to do what to find someone in any book like this?
赔率是我们大多数人会在这样的书中找到找人的东西吗？
Yeah.
是啊。
Open to roughly the middle or maybe bias ourselves toward the end
向大致中间开放或者可能偏向最后
because S is after the middle.
因为S在中间之后。
But you know, I'm in the middle of the phonebook here.
但是你知道，我在这里的电话簿中间。
And now, if I know that Mike is in the S's and therefore over here,
而现在，如果我知道Mike在S中，因此在这里，
where do I know he's not?
我在哪里知道他不是？
He's not in the beginning and I can literally
他不是在开始，我可以字面意思
tear a problem like this in half, throw figuratively and literally half
把这样的问题撕成两半，比喻地丢掉一半
of the problem away, and be left with fundamentally the same problem,
问题的消失，并留下基本相同的问题，
but it's half as big.
但它的一半大。
I went from like-- whatever--
我喜欢 - 不管 -
1,000 pages to 500 pages and I can now repeat this algorithm.
1,000页到500页，我现在可以重复这个算法。
I look down.
我低下头。
I'm a little too far.
我有点太过分了。
I'm in the T section now.
我现在在T部分。
OK.
好。
I can again tear the problem in half, throw that half away,
我可以再将问题撕成两半，扔掉一半，
taking a 500 page byte out, a 250 page byte out, now leaving myself
取出500页的字节，一个250页的字节输出，现在离开了我自己
with just 250 pages more.
只有250页。
And notice just how quickly I got here.
请注意我到达这里的速度有多快。
The first two algorithms got me from 1,000 to 999 to 998, or 1,000 to 998
前两个算法让我从1,000到999到998，或1,000到998
to 996.
到996。
But here, I went from 1,000 to 500 to 250.
但在这里，我从1,000到500到250。
Feels like we're making up time here.
感觉就像我们在这里弥补时间。
And indeed, if I keep repeating this process,
事实上，如果我不断重复这个过程，
hopefully, I'll be left with just one page of the book
希望，我只剩下这本书的一页
that Mike is either on or not, at which point, I will call him.
迈克是否参加，此时我会打电话给他。
And so that's an algorithm that honestly leverages probably all the intuition we
所以这是一个诚实地利用我们所有直觉的算法
have and a lot of what programming is going to be,
有很多编程将会是，
is thinking about a problem like this, figuring out how to divide and conquer
正在考虑这样的问题，弄清楚如何划分和征服
it, and then expressing yourself in a way
它，然后以某种方式表达自己
that the computer can then solve that problem for you.
然后，计算机可以为您解决该问题。
And just to paint a picture of how much better this algorithm is, well,
只是为了描绘这个算法有多好，嗯，
if this is just a very abstract chart where we have on the vertical,
如果这只是我们在垂直方向上的一个非常抽象的图表，
or y-axis, how much time it takes to solve a problem,
或y轴，解决问题需要多长时间，
and on the horizontal axis how big the problem is--
在横轴上问题有多大 -
so the farther out you go this way, the more pages in the problem,
所以越走越远，问题中的页面越多，
the more pages in the phonebook.
电话簿中的页面越多。
And the higher you go up here, the more seconds or page
你在这里越高，秒数或页数越多
turns it's going to take.
转过身来。
That first algorithm is just like a linear slope,
第一个算法就像一个线性斜率，
so to speak, because for every additional page in the book,
可以这么说，因为对于书中的每一页，
it might take me one more second.
它可能需要我一秒钟。
Right, up.
马上。
It's just a one for one relationship with pages.
这只是与页面的一对一关系。
The second algorithm, if I plot it, where
第二种算法，如果我绘制它，在哪里
I'm flying through twice as fast, what is
我飞得快了两倍，是什么
that line going to look like instead?
那条线看起来像？
Yeah.
是啊。
It's going to look lower than this one.
它看起来比这个要低。
It's still going to be a straight line because now, there's a two to one
它仍然是一条直线，因为现在有两比一
relationship, but if you've got a phone book that's got this many pages,
关系，但如果你有一本有这么多页面的电话簿，
and in the first algorithm, it took this long, here,
在第一个算法中，花了很长时间，在这里，
well, in the second algorithm, it will take half as many steps, plus or minus
好吧，在第二种算法中，它将需要一半的步数，加或减
or two if you need to actually double back a little bit.
或两个，如果你需要实际翻倍一点。
But that third algorithm is what we'll call logarithmic.
但是第三种算法就是我们称之为对数的算法。
If n is the number of pages in the phone book,
如果n是电话簿中的页数，
the first algorithm, in the very worst case,
第一种算法，在最坏的情况下，
might take all n pages to find Mike Smith.
可能需要所有n页才能找到Mike Smith。
The second algorithm is going to take half as many steps because I'm
第二种算法将采取一半的步骤，因为我
flying through it two at a time.
一次两个飞过它。
But the third algorithm is going to look and feel like this.
但第三种算法看起来和感觉都是这样的。
It's going to be curved and ever so slowly rising and rising and rising,
它将是弯曲的，并且如此缓慢地上升，上升和上升，
the implication of which is if Verizon or the phone company
其中的含义是Verizon或电话公司
doubles the number of pages in the phonebook
将电话簿中的页数加倍
next year because Cambridge and Somerville merged together in the phone
明年因为剑桥和萨默维尔在电话中合并在一起
book and we now have 2,000 pages.
我们现在有2,000页。
Well, how many more steps does my third algorithm take?
那么，我的第三个算法需要多少步骤？
Just one.
只有一个。
Because I can take a 1,000 page bite out of the problem
因为我可以从问题中拿出1000页
with that clever algorithm, whereas my first two algorithms would take it
用这个聪明的算法，而我的前两个算法将采取它
one or just two pages at a time.
一次一页或两页。
So that is to say we have to hugely increase the size of this problem
所以这就是说我们必须大大增加这个问题的规模
just for the number of seconds or page turns to appreciably actually increase.
只是因为秒数或页面转弯明显增加。
And so as we start to learn about programming,
因此，当我们开始学习编程时，
it's, again, going to be leveraging of this intuition in order
再次，它将依次利用这种直觉
to actually solve problems and code more effectively than we
实际上比我们更有效地解决问题和代码
might without that intuition alone.
可能没有那种直觉。
So let's formalize this now.
所以让我们现在正式化。
So that was kind of a very intuitive way of dividing and conquering a problem.
因此，这是一种非常直观的分解和征服问题的方式。
Just kind of made sense to go in the middle,
走进中间是有道理的，
tear it, then go to the other half or the other half
撕掉它，然后去另一半或另一半
and tear it again, and so forth.
再把它撕掉，等等。
But a computer, even as cool as Alexa and Google Home and all of this are,
但是，计算机，甚至像Alexa和Google Home一样酷，所有这些都是，
you can't really just talk to them as another human
你不能真正与他们作为另一个人交谈
and have them execute things correctly.
让他们正确地执行事情。
I struggle just to get Siri to set a timer on my phone.
我很难让Siri在我的手机上设置计时器。
So we're not quite there yet, so we're still at the age
所以我们还没到那里，所以我们还处于这个时代
where we have to be ever so precise with computers,
我们必须在计算机上如此精确，
voice activated or otherwise, and so thus enter pseudocode for now.
语音激活或其他方式，因此现在进入伪代码。
Pseudocode has no formal definition.
伪代码没有正式的定义。
This is just a way of saying use English like syntax or any spoken language
这只是说使用英语语法或任何口语的一种方式
and just express yourself succinctly and correctly
并且只是简洁而正确地表达自己
so that a computer or a robot or even another person
使计算机或机器人甚至是另一个人
can understand what it is you're trying to say.
可以理解你想说的是什么。
So here, I propose, is an algorithm written
所以在这里，我建议，是一种编写的算法
in pseudocode, English like syntax, that just gets my point across.
在伪代码中，英语就像语法一样，这只是我的观点。
And I could write this in any number of ways.
我可以用多种方式写出来。
I've numbered the steps from zero on up, just for the sake of discussion,
为了讨论，我已经从零开始编号，只是为了讨论，
but this would seem to capture what I did there.
但这似乎捕获了我在那里所做的事情。
Pick up the phone book.
拿起电话簿。
Open to the middle of the phone.
打开电话中间。
Look at the names.
看看名字。
If Smith is among the names, call Mike.
如果史密斯是其中的名字，请致电迈克。
Else, if Mike Smith is earlier in the book,
否则，如果迈克史密斯在书的前面，
go to the left, specifically the middle of the left half of the book,
走到左边，特别是书的左半部分的中间，
and then go back to step two.
然后回到第二步。
Because indeed, I was just doing the same thing again and again,
因为的确，我只是一次又一次地做同样的事情，
and the reason I wasn't doing it forever was because every time I
我不是永远这样做的原因是因为我每次都这样做
repeated myself by opening and tearing, I was shrinking the problem.
通过开放和撕裂重复自己，我正在缩小问题。
And I can only shrink a problem of some fixed finite size
我只能缩小一些固定有限大小的问题
so many times until I get just one page, and so
这么多次，直到我只有一页，等等
if I continue this logic looking to the right or to the left or just quitting,
如果我继续这个逻辑向右或向左看，或者只是放弃，
if I don't find Mike at all on the last page,
如果我在最后一页上找不到迈克，
this would seem to capture more precisely that code.
这似乎更准确地捕获了代码。
Well, let's actually excerpt from this now a few concepts
好吧，我们现在实际上摘录了一些概念
and then start to apply them to actual code.
然后开始将它们应用于实际代码。
Highlighted in yellow here, I dare say, are all of the verbs or actions.
我敢说，这里用黄色突出显示的是所有的动词或动作。
These are the functions, as we're going to start calling them,
这些是函数，因为我们将开始调用它们，
in this algorithm.
在这个算法中。
A function is just a specific step, a specific action
功能只是一个特定的步骤，一个特定的动作
you take in order to do something.
你需要做某事。
And so in yellow here-- pick up, open to, look at, call, open, quit
所以黄色在这里 - 拿起，打开，看，打电话，打开，退出
are all actions or verbs.
都是动作或动词。
Are henceforth, we'll call them functions.
从此以后，我们称之为功能。
Meanwhile, highlighted in yellow here-- if, else if, else if, else.
同时，在这里以黄色突出显示 - 如果，否则如果，否则如果，否则。
These are kind of starting to ask questions.
这些都是开始提问的一种方式。
What might these be called if you have some familiarity?
如果你有一些熟悉的话可能会被称为什么？
Yes.
是。
Turns out many programming languages, if you've seen any before,
如果你以前看过任何编程语言，那么结果很多，
would call these conditions.
会称之为这些条件。
They're branches, or proverbial forks in the road.
他们是道路上的分支机构或众所周知的叉子。
If this is true, go this way.
如果这是真的，那就这样吧。
Else, maybe go this other way, or perhaps a third or fourth direction
否则，可能会采取另一种方式，或者可能是第三或第四方向
altogether.
共。
Meanwhile, if we actually look at these highlighted phrases--
同时，如果我们真正看到这些突出的短语 -
if Smith is among names or if Smith is earlier in book
如果史密斯是名人之间，或史密斯是早期的书
or Smith is later in book--
或史密斯后来在书中 -
these are the specific questions we're asking in order to make that decision.
这些是我们为了做出这个决定而要求的具体问题。
These are known as Boolean expressions, named after a gentleman
这些被称为布尔表达式，以绅士的名字命名
by the last name of Boole some years ago.
几年前以Boole的姓氏命名。
And so a Boolean expression is just a question
因此布尔表达式只是一个问题
that has a yes or no answer, a true false answer, a one zero
有一个是或否答案，一个真正的错误答案，一个零
answer, if you will.
回答，如果你愿意的话。
And that's a nice mapping to what computers are really good at.
这对于计算机真正擅长的是一个很好的映射。
So within conditions, you have Boolean expressions
所以在条件中，你有布尔表达式
to decide which fork in the road you want to go down.
决定你想要走的路上哪个叉子。
And then lastly, highlighted in yellow here
最后，在这里以黄色突出显示
is go back to step 2 in a couple of places.
在几个地方回到第2步。
This is inducing some kind of cycle or loop
这是诱导某种循环或循环
that's telling the computer to do something again and again and again.
这告诉计算机一次又一次地做某事。
So in short, we have these building blocks already conceptually.
简而言之，我们已经在概念上拥有这些构建块。
And it turns out, we can now start to translate these
事实证明，我们现在可以开始翻译它们了
to an actual programming language.
一种实际的编程语言。
The first of the languages we'll introduce in CS50
我们将在CS50中介绍的第一种语言
is something called Scratch.
是一个叫做Scratch的东西。
Turns out this is not a text based language,
事实证明这不是基于文本的语言，
like in my English pseudocode there, but it's graphical
比如我的英文伪代码，但它是图形化的
and things look like puzzle pieces that you can drag and drop
事物看起来像你可以拖放的拼图
and they interconnect if it makes logical sense to do so.
如果这样做有逻辑意义，它们会相互连接。
And in fact, some of you might have played this back in the day as kids
事实上，有些人可能会像孩子一样在当天玩这个
or even more recently because it's actually targeted typically
甚至更近，因为它实际上是针对性的
at students in like after school programs who
在学生喜欢放学后的课程
just want to learn more methodical, more algorithmic, or computational thinking.
只是想学习更多有条理，更算法或计算思维。
And we're going to use it to explore not only these building
而且我们将用它来探索这些建筑
blocks, but a few others, as well.
块，但也有一些。
It turns out in the other languages we'll explore in CS50 and beyond,
事实证明，我们将在CS50及更高版本中探索其他语言，
are languages like C that we'll actually transition to as quickly as next week,
像C这样的语言我们实际上会在下周快速过渡到
to then translate what we do this week in Scratch to next week in C.
然后将我们本周在Scratch中所做的事情转换为下周的C语言。
And in languages like Python and JavaScript
在Python和JavaScript等语言中
and SQL, which we'll also explore, do we have other capabilities--
和SQL，我们也将探讨，我们还有其他功能 -
the ability to store data in variables, so to speak,
能够将数据存储在变量中，可以这么说
to use threads, which means get the computer to do multiple things at once,
使用线程，这意味着让计算机一次做多件事，
events, to mean listen for things happening, like a click
事件，意味着倾听发生的事情，比如点击
on the page or a human typing or even saying something.
在页面上或人类打字甚至说些什么。
We'll be able to do all of the things that you take
我们将能够完成你所做的所有事情
for granted in your very own phones.
在你自己的手机中是理所当然的。
And we'll do this first by way of this guy.
我们首先会通过这个人来做这件事。
So this is Scratch, the default cat that comes with this programming
所以这是Scratch，这个编程附带的默认猫
language from MIT's media lab.
来自麻省理工学院媒体实验室的语言。
And via Scratch can we start programming him to move up,
通过Scratch，我们可以开始编程让他向上移动，
down, left, right, say something, utter something, and other commands
向下，向左，向右，说些什么，说出什么，以及其他命令
all together.
全部一起。
In fact, let me go ahead and switch contexts here
事实上，让我继续前进并切换上下文
to show you the very first thing I ever wrote in Scratch.
告诉你我在Scratch写的第一件事。
It was back in the day when I was in graduate school
那是在我读研究生的那天
and Scratch had just been invented by MIT.
和Scratch刚刚由麻省理工学院发明。
Let me go ahead and open this.
让我继续吧。
And I called it Oscar Time.
我把它称为奥斯卡时间。
And if we could perhaps have a volunteer come on up for just a moment.
如果我们可以让一名志愿者上场片刻。
You have to be comfortable being on stage and on the internet.
你必须在舞台上和互联网上感到很舒服。
How about here in the white shirt?
穿白衬衫怎么样？
I saw your hand first.
我先看到了你的手。
Come on down.
下来吧。
So this is Oscar Time.
所以这是奥斯卡时间。
It's implemented in a language called Scratch.
它是用Scratch语言实现的。
And at the end of the day, all that is underneath the hood of this program
在一天结束时，所有这一切都在这个程序的引擎盖下
is functions and loops and conditions and a few other of these concepts.
是函数和循环和条件以及这些概念中的一些其他概念。
Hi.
你好。
What's your name?
你叫什么名字？
AVIVA: Aviva.
AVIVA：英杰华。
DAVID MALAN: Aviva.
大卫马兰：英杰华。
David.
大卫。
Nice to meet you.
很高兴见到你。
Come on over here.
来吧，来吧
And in just a moment, I'm going to go ahead and click
过了一会儿，我要继续点击
the green flag at the top left hand corner, which
左上角的绿旗，哪个
is going to play this game.
打算玩这个游戏。
And we'll see on the screen the instructions.
我们会在屏幕上看到说明。
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
OSCAR: (SINGING) Oh, I love trash.
奥斯卡:(唱歌）哦，我喜欢垃圾。
Anything dirty or dingy or dusty.
任何肮脏或肮脏或尘土飞扬的东西。
Anything ragged or rotten or rusty.
任何衣衫褴褛，腐烂或生锈的东西。
Yes, I love trash.
是的，我喜欢垃圾。
If you really want to see something trashy, look at this.
如果你真的想看到一些无用的东西，那就看看吧。
I have here a sneaker that's tattered and worn.
我这里有一个破旧破旧的运动鞋。
It's all full of holes and the laces are torn.
它全是洞，鞋带被撕裂。
A gift from my mother the day I was born.
我出生那天送给母亲的礼物。
I love it because it's trash.
我喜欢它，因为它是垃圾。
Oh, I love trash.
哦，我喜欢垃圾。
Anything dirty or dingy or dusty.
任何肮脏或肮脏或尘土飞扬的东西。
Anything ragged or rotten or rusty.
任何衣衫褴褛，腐烂或生锈的东西。
Yes, I love trash.
是的，我喜欢垃圾。
Here's some more rotten stuff.
这是一些更腐烂的东西。
I have here some newspaper 13 months old.
我这里有一些13个月大的报纸。
DAVID MALAN: All right.
大卫马兰：好的。
Everybody, give a round of applause for Aviva for coming on up.
每个人都为Aviva的掌声鼓掌。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Here.
这里。
Aviva.
英杰。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
A little CS50 stress ball.
一点点CS50压力球。
So suffice it to say, if you're tired of this song,
这足以说，如果你厌倦了这首歌，
consider how tired I was eight hours later while debugging and building
考虑一下8小时后我在调试和构建时有多累
this program.
这个计划。
But consider what it is we just saw.
但请考虑一下我们刚看到的内容。
It's this interactive game and stuff is animated and music is playing.
这是这个互动游戏，东西是动画和音乐正在播放。
But if you focus on decomposing, so to speak, this program into just
但是，如果你专注于分解，可以这么说，这个程序只是
basic building blocks, this is just kind of a big abstraction over some lower
基本构建块，这只是一些较低层次的大抽象
level pieces of functionality.
级别的功能。
Like this trash can here.
像这样的垃圾桶在这里。
At the moment, it's just a picture, and on occasion,
目前，它只是一张照片，有时，
as soon as Aviva dropped something into the trash, the lid came up
一旦Aviva将东西扔进垃圾桶，盖子就会出现
and Oscar came out, he said something, and then he went back down.
奥斯卡出来了，他说了些什么，然后又回去了。
But that animation is super simplistic.
但那个动画超级简单。
It was just a sequence of 1, 2, 3, or so images displaying and then
它只是一个显示1,2,3或更多图像的序列然后显示
going back down to create the illusion of animation.
回去创造动画的幻觉。
Meanwhile, every time Oscar said something,
与此同时，每当奥斯卡说出一些话，
that was keeping track of her score in what's called a variable.
那是在所谓的变量中跟踪她的得分。
In algebra, you have x and y and z, but in programming, you have the same idea,
在代数中，你有x和y和z，但在编程中，你有同样的想法，
but it's generally more useful to call them more descriptively,
但通常更具描述性地称呼它们更有用，
like your score.
喜欢你的分数。
And so there's probably a variable in this game called
所以在这个游戏中可能有一个变量叫做
score that was just keeping track of how many times
得分只是跟踪多少次
Aviva had dropped something into the trash.
英杰华把东西丢进垃圾桶里。
Meanwhile, the trash itself and the shoe and the newspaper-- and even more
与此同时，垃圾本身，鞋子和报纸 - 甚至更多
things happen eventually-- were falling from the sky
事情最终会发生 - 从天而降
at sort of random locations, and that's because I programmed the game
在某种随机位置，这是因为我编写了游戏
to sort of start the trash here or over here, just
只是为了在这里或在这里开始垃圾
to make it a little more challenging as the game picked up.
随着比赛的进行，让比赛变得更具挑战性。
And in fact, things start falling faster and faster over time,
事实上，随着时间的推移，事情开始越来越快，
like a typical game, getting more and more difficult.
像一个典型的游戏，变得越来越困难。
So how do we get to something like that?
那么我们如何得到类似的东西呢？
Well, let me go ahead and open up Scratch itself
好吧，让我继续开放Scratch本身
and introduce the environment.
并介绍环境。
So in Scratch, you essentially have three general areas.
所以在Scratch中，你基本上有三个一般领域。
And it's web based, and so you can do this on any computer.
它是基于网络的，因此您可以在任何计算机上执行此操作。
And in the left hand side here, you have those puzzle pieces
在这里的左侧，你有那些拼图
to which I referred earlier.
我刚才提到的。
These puzzle pieces are all mapping to functions or loops or conditions
这些拼图都映射到函数或循环或条件
or variables, things that we saw before, and I'm
或变量，我们之前看到的事情，我是
going to able to drag and drop them into the middle in order
能够将它们按顺序拖放到中间
to interconnect them and write my program,
将它们互连并编写我的程序，
which we'll do in just a moment.
我们马上就会做的。
Meanwhile, Scratch lives in this stage, this world, where he can move up,
与此同时，Scratch生活在这个阶段，这个世界，他可以向上移动，
down, left, right.
向下，向左，向右。
You can change what Scratch looks like.
你可以改变Scratch的样子。
You can add other characters, otherwise known as sprites,
你可以添加其他字符，也称为精灵，
in order to have multiple things happening at once.
为了让一次发生多件事。
And of course, you can fullscreen it.
当然，你可以全屏显示它。
And so the Oscar Time game a moment ago was actually a whole bunch of sprites.
所以刚才的奥斯卡时间游戏实际上是一大堆精灵。
Oscar's trash can was one.
奥斯卡的垃圾桶就是其中之一。
Each piece of trash was another sprite.
每一块垃圾都是另一个精灵。
The newspaper was a sprite, and so forth.
报纸是精灵，等等。
So each of them were separate programs running in parallel at the same time.
因此，它们中的每一个都是同时并行运行的独立程序。
So let's actually make him do something.
所以，让我真正让他做点什么。
It turns out that if I jump down to, say, events,
事实证明，如果我跳到事件，
I'm going to see one of the most powerful blocks
我将看到一个最强大的块
from the get go, which is this when green flag clicked.
从开始，这是绿色标志点击时。
That's indeed how I started the game with Aviva,
这就是我与Aviva开始游戏的方式，
by clicking just above Scratch's world this green flag.
通过点击Scratch世界这个绿色标志。
And if I wanted to stop it, as I did, you
如果我想阻止它，就像我一样，你
can click the red stop sign to say stop.
可以点击红色停止标志说停止。
Meanwhile, the green flag, I can constantly
同时，绿旗，我可以不断
listen for by dragging and dropping this puzzle piece.
通过拖放这个拼图来听。
When the green flag is clicked, what do I want to do?
点击绿色标志后，我想做什么？
Well, let me go up to looks.
好吧，让我去看看。
And these are just different categories.
这些只是不同的类别。
And we can scroll through all the different colorful blocks,
我们可以滚动浏览所有不同的彩色块，
but they pretty much just do what they say.
但他们几乎只是做他们说的话。
I'm going to go under looks, where I know there to be a block that's called
我会去看看，我知道那里有一个叫做的块
say, and I'm going to go ahead and type the most canonical computer science
比如说，我将继续选择最规范的计算机科学
thing-- hello world--
东西 - 你好世界 -
in this box.
在这个盒子里。
So notice that functions themselves can actually
所以注意功能本身实际上可以
take inputs and the input to this function, say,
拿输入和输入这个功能，比方说，
is going to be hello world.
将成为你好世界。
If I now go over to the green flag and click it--
如果我现在去绿旗并点击它 -
hello world.
你好，世界。
All right.
行。
So not all that difficult. Not all that interesting.
所以不是那么困难。不是那么有趣。
But it actually got the job done, and so my program is indeed just this.
但它确实完成了工作，所以我的计划确实就是这样。
Well, how might I make this a little more interesting?
那么，我怎么能让这个更有趣呢？
Just saying, hello world all the time isn't all that compelling.
只是说，你好世界并不是那么引人注目。
Well, you know what?
嗯，你知道吗？
Let me think.
让我想想。
Let me undo this.
让我撤消这个。
Let me scroll down to sensing.
让我向下滚动到感应。
And notice this.
请注意这一点。
Functions can also take input from a human
函数也可以从人类输入
and functions can hand you back a value, a so-called return value.
并且函数可以将一个值（一个所谓的返回值）交还给您。
So this block here, ask something-- by default, it says,
所以这个块在这里，问一些东西 - 默认情况下，它说，
what's your name and weight--
你的名字和体重是多少 -
is another function built into Scratch that allows me to do this.
是Scratch内置的另一个功能，允许我这样做。
So I'm going to go ahead and drag this here
所以我要继续把它拖到这里
and I'm going to let it say, what's your name?
我会说，你叫什么名字？
Notice now that below this block is a special block,
现在请注意，此块下面是一个特殊块，
whatever it is the block returns.
无论块返回什么。
So answer is whatever the human is going to type in.
所以答案就是人类要输入的内容。
And if I want to now say what the human typed in, let me go again to looks.
如果我现在要说出人类所输入的内容，让我再去看看。
Go to say.
去说吧。
And notice that these blocks are kind of magnetic.
并注意到这些块是有点磁性的。
They want to snap together.
他们想要拼凑在一起。
So I'm going to go ahead and let go there.
所以我要继续前进，放手去那里。
And if I go back to sensing and grab answer,
如果我回到传感并抓住答案，
notice that even though it's not quite the same size,
请注意，即使它的大小不一样，
it's going to grow to fill, and now, I can
它会成长，现在，我可以
have my program ask the user what his or her name is and then
让我的程序询问用户他或她的名字是什么然后
say whatever that answer is.
说出答案是什么。
So let me go ahead and stop and click play again.
所以让我继续前进并停止并再次点击播放。
Notice it's asking me for my name, so let me go ahead and type in David.
注意它是在问我的名字，所以让我继续输入大卫。
Enter.
输入。
OK.
好。
It's a little weird way to greet someone.
迎接某人有点奇怪的方式。
David.
大卫。
So it'd be nice to clean that up a bit.
所以清理它有点好。
So you know what?
所以你知道吗？
I know this only from having poked around before.
我知道这只是因为之前已经戳过。
Not all of this is obvious at first glance.
乍一看并非所有这些都是显而易见的。
But it turns out that under operators, the category,
但事实证明，在运营商，类别，
there's this thing here-- join apple and banana.
这里有这个东西 - 加入苹果和香蕉。
Which are just default values.
这只是默认值。
You can change them.
你可以改变它们。
Because what do I want to do?
因为我想做什么？
I want to say hello, David, or whoever, so I kind of want to say hello, comma,
我想打招呼，大卫，或者其他任何人，所以我有点想打个招呼，逗号，
and then, David-- whatever the human typed in.
然后，大卫 - 无论人类输入什么。
And that's what join lets you do.
这就是加入让你做的事情。
It lets you join or concatenate two phrases that are somehow
它允许您以某种方式连接或连接两个短语
provided by you or the user.
由您或用户提供。
So let me pull this out, the answer.
所以，让我把它拉出来，答案。
Let me go ahead and grab the join block.
让我继续前进并抓住连接块。
Notice it, too, is going to grow to fill.
请注意，它也会增长。
Let me go ahead and say, hello, comma, space, and now, drag answer into there.
让我继续说，你好，逗号，空间，现在，把答案拖到那里。
And notice this nesting.
注意这个嵌套。
Just like in math.
就像数学一样。
This nesting of functions.
这种功能嵌套。
I can first join hello and answer by taking those two things as input
我可以先把这两件事作为输入加入你好并回答
and then pass them to say as another input
然后传递给他们说另一个输入
because these things are layered on top.
因为这些东西都是分层的。
And so now, if I stop this and play it again and say, David--
所以现在，如果我停下来再玩一遍并说，大卫 -
hello, David.
你好，大卫。
Now, we have the makings of a more interesting interactive program
现在，我们有一个更有趣的交互式程序的材料
that isn't just hardcoded.
这不仅仅是硬编码。
Of course, it's not nearly as audible as something like Oscar Time a moment ago.
当然，它几乎不像奥斯卡时代那样可听见。
So let me go ahead and do this.
所以让我继续这样做。
Let me start over altogether and treat Scratch like the cat he is
让我重新开始，像对待猫一样对待Scratch
and just start the sound called meow.
然后开始叫喵喵的声音。
So it turns out there's a category of blocks called sound,
所以事实证明有一类称为声音的块，
and within sound, there is play some default sounds.
在声音中，播放一些默认声音。
So start sound meow.
所以开始喵喵叫。
And now, things will get a little cuter.
现在，事情会变得有点可爱。
[MEOW]
[喵]
Aw.
噢。
And now, again.
现在，又来了。
[MEOW]
[喵]
And I can kind of simulate a cat by [MEOW] standing here for a while
我可以通过[MEOW]模拟一只猫站在这里一段时间
and keeping to click this button.
并保持单击此按钮。
But you know what?
但你知道吗？
Let me make him meow few times because that's more realistic.
让我喵喵几次，因为那更加现实。
So let me grab a second one and a third one.
所以让我抓住第二个和第三个。
And you can get this infinite supply of blocks.
而且你可以获得无限的块供应。
Let me hit play.
让我来玩。
[MEOW]
[喵]
Seems like a bug.
好像是个bug。
Let's try again.
让我们再试一次。
Play.
玩。
[MEOW]
[喵]
This is my first bug, or mistake.
这是我的第一个错误或错误。
This looks correct.
这看起来很正确。
It says when green flag clicked, start sound meow, start sound meow,
它说绿色标志点击时，开始声音喵喵，开始声音喵喵，
start sound meow.
开始喵喵叫。
Why am I only hearing one meow?
为什么我只听一个喵？
Yeah.
是啊。
They're kind of at the same time or so close to the same time
它们在同一时间或同时接近同一时间
that the sounds are kind of tripping over each other and just overlapping,
声音有点绊倒，只是重叠，
right?
对？
The block literally says, start sound meow.
字面上说，块开始声音喵喵。
But computers are really fast.
但电脑真的很快。
If you've heard of the expression gigahertz, that's a unit of measure.
如果你听说过gigahertz的表达式，那就是衡量单位。
And if your computer has a one gigahertz CPU, central processing unit, or brain,
如果您的计算机有一个千兆赫的CPU，中央处理单元或大脑，
that means it can literally do like a billion things per second.
这意味着它每秒可以完成十亿件事。
It can certainly start three sounds super fast.
它当然可以超快速地启动三种声音。
And if they're effectively all happening one after the other
如果他们真的一个接一个地发生
before the sound even finishes, you're just hearing one net effect.
在声音结束之前，你只是听到一个净效果。
So how can we fix this?
那我们怎么解决这个问题呢？
Well, I can actually go and fix this with this block here--
好吧，我实际上可以用这个块来解决这个问题 -
play sound meow until done.
发出声音喵喵直到完成。
Play sound meow until done.
播放声音喵喵直到完成。
And now.
现在。
[MEOWING]
[喵喵叫]
OK.
好。
It's a little unhappy, this particular cat,
有点不高兴，这只特别的猫，
but at least it's now more correct.
但至少它现在更正确了。
And, as it turns out, if I go to control--
事实证明，如果我去控制 -
you know what?
你知道吗？
There's this block here-- wait some number of seconds.
这里有这个块 - 等待几秒钟。
I can go ahead and insert this here.
我可以继续这里插入。
Let me do another one here.
我在这里再做一次。
And now, hit play.
现在，点击播放。
[MEOWING]
[喵喵叫]
You know, it's not bad.
你知道，这还不错。
It now sounds a little more realistic.
现在听起来更加真实。
But honestly, if I keep doing this-- or you know what?
但老实说，如果我继续这样做 - 或者你知道吗？
You can actually right click or control click on blocks,
您实际上可以右键单击或控制单击块，
duplicate them, and just copy and paste even more if you want them.
复制它们，如果需要，只需复制和粘贴即可。
So if I were to do this, now, it's just going to go six times.
所以，如果我这样做，现在，它只会去六次。
And then I could copy it again and go 12 times.
然后我可以再次复制并去12次。
But there's got to be a better way, right?
但是必须有更好的方法，对吧？
This is now bad programming.
现在这是糟糕的编程。
This is bad design.
这是糟糕的设计。
Because I'm literally copying and pasting, albeit, graphically.
因为我实际上是在复制和粘贴，尽管是图形化的。
But we've already seen a building block with which
但是我们已经看到了一个构建块
we can design this program better.
我们可以更好地设计这个程序。
It's correct, but it's not well designed.
这是正确的，但设计不合理。
What would the building block be that I need to make this a little cleaner?
我需要用什么构建块来使它更干净一点？
OK.
好。
A four loop.
一个四循环。
Doesn't quite exist in Scratch.
在Scratch中不存在。
But a loop fundamentally does something cyclically.
但循环从根本上会循环地做一些事情。
And indeed, if I go under control and start poking around,
事实上，如果我受到控制并开始探索，
you'll notice that there's a few blocks that might apply here.
你会注意到这里有一些可能适用的块。
There's the repeat block some number of times
重复阻止了很多次
or the forever block, both of which sound like loops, or cycles.
或永远的块，两者听起来像循环或循环。
So sure enough, let me go ahead here and I can throw away blocks
当然，让我继续前进，我可以扔掉积木
by just dragging them to the left.
只需将它们拖到左侧即可。
Let me pull this out for a second.
让我把它拉出来一秒钟。
And then just say forever play this sound, and then wait one second.
然后就说永远播放这个声音，然后等一秒钟。
So now, my program looks like this.
所以现在，我的程序看起来像这样。
[MEOWING]
[喵喵叫]
You know, we'll never know if it's technically correct because it's just
你知道，我们永远不会知道它是否在技术上是正确的，因为它只是
going to go, we think, forever, but it looks like this is correct.
我们认为永远都会去，但看起来这是正确的。
And it was a lot less code and it's a lot easier
它的代码少得多，而且更容易
to maintain because if I want him to kind of get sleepy,
维持，因为如果我想让他变得困倦，
I can then maybe say two seconds instead.
然后我可以说两秒钟。
[MEOW]
[喵]
You know, and we can adjust this on the fly as we go.
你知道，我们可以随时随地调整。
But let's start to combine some of these ideas
但是，让我们开始结合其中的一些想法
now and change what it is the ultimate effect is.
现在，改变它的最终效果是什么。
Let me go ahead and open an example I made in advance.
让我继续，打开一个我提前做的例子。
This one's called Count Zero.
这个名叫Count Zero。
And we'll put this on the website later so that you can play with if you like.
我们稍后会将它放在网站上，以便您可以随意使用。
And this is kind of the opposite of counting sheep.
这与数羊相反。
Rather than me or the person sleeping counting sheep,
而不是我或睡觉的人数羊，
this sheep will count itself.
这只羊会算数。
So let me go ahead and just play.
所以让我继续前进吧。
And adorably, he seems to just be counting 1, 2, 3.
而且很可能，他似乎只计算1,2,3。
But why is that?
但那是为什么呢？
He's just going to count forever.
他只会永远数数。
But let's look at the blocks with which he is counting forever.
但是，让我们看看他永远计数的街区。
When green flag clicked, set counter.
单击绿色标记时，设置计数器。
Turns out this orange box is what we called a variable.
原来这个橙色框是我们所谓的变量。
So in algebra, it would be like x or y or z.
所以在代数中，它就像x或y或z。
Those are not descriptive.
那些不是描述性的。
I called this one counter instead, but I could have called it x or y or z.
我把它称为一个计数器，但我可以将其称为x或y或z。
And then I forever say the counter for one second, then wait one second,
然后我永远地说计数器一秒钟，然后等一秒钟，
and then change the counter by one, which
然后将计数器改为1，其中
technically means just increment it.
技术上意味着只是增加它。
Add 1 to it.
加1吧。
And the sheep is just going to therefore count up and up and up.
因此，绵羊只会计数起来。
Now, this is a little tedious, but that's
现在，这有点乏味，但那是
kind of the point of counting sheep, of course, to fall asleep.
有点像数羊，当然要睡着了。
But what if the sheep actually kind of liked counting a little faster?
但是，如果羊实际上喜欢计数更快一点怎么办？
Well, let me go under operators here.
好吧，让我去这里的运营商。
Multiplication sounds like it could get us places quicker.
乘法听起来像它可以让我们更快地放置。
And let me go ahead and go to variables.
让我继续前进并转向变量。
And instead of changing the counter by one,
而不是将计数器改为1，
let me go ahead and just keep setting it to something else.
让我继续，继续把它设置为其他东西。
So let me drag and drop this.
所以让我拖放一下。
Set the counter equal to something times something, specifically
特别是将计数器设置为某种东西
the counter times two, thereby doubling, doubling, doubling, doubling.
计数器乘以两次，从而加倍，加倍，加倍，加倍。
That would seem to grow, so to speak, a lot faster.
可以说，这似乎会增长得更快。
Let's see.
让我们来看看。
1, 2, 4.
1,2,4。
So he's counting faster, but it's still kind of tedious.
所以他的数量更快，但仍然有点单调乏味。
What if we instead do this?
如果我们改为做怎么办？
Let's stop waiting and let's go ahead and, with the looks,
让我们停止等待，让我们继续前进，看看，
not say counter for one second, but let's just quickly say counter.
不要说反击一秒钟，但让我们快速说反击。
So I'm going to say the counter.
所以我要说反击。
Whoops.
哎呦。
I'm going to say the counter and then I'm going to set it to itself times 2.
我要说计数器，然后我要把它设置为自己的时间2。
So here's where we're at.
所以这就是我们所处的位置。
Initialize, or set the counter to 1 initially, say it, then double it,
初始化，或者首先将计数器设置为1，然后将其加倍，
then double it, then double it, saying it along the way.
然后加倍，然后加倍，一路上说。
So here we go.
所以我们走了。
That's impressive.
这很让人佩服。
So now the sheep has counted up to 10 to the 60th so far.
所以现在羊到目前为止已经计到了10到60。
10 to the 100th.
10到100。
OK.
好。
Now, it doesn't even fit in the speech bubble, but he's still going.
现在，它甚至不适合讲话泡泡，但他还在继续。
How high can he go?
他能走多远？
What's the biggest number you can count to in a computer?
计算机中最重要的数字是多少？
Anyone want to guess?
有人想猜吗？
Could be here a while.
可能会在这里一段时间。
10 to the 270th now.
现在10到270号。
How high can you count, or rather--
你有多高，或者更确切地说 -
OK.
好。
So we gave up and just called it infinity.
所以我们放弃了，只是称它为无限。
So it turns out infinity does have a precise value--
所以事实证明无限确实有一个确切的价值 -
10 to the 250th or so.
10到250左右。
But what happens here?
但这里发生了什么？
Well, because computers, at the end of the day,
好吧，因为电脑，在一天结束时，
are just storing information digitally-- but that information digitally has
只是以数字方式存储信息 - 但这些信息是数字化的
to be physically stored using electricity, using these lower level
使用这些较低级别使用电力进行物理存储
switches called transistors.
开关称为晶体管。
At the end of the day, my phone, my laptop, whatever device in question
在一天结束时，我的手机，笔记本电脑，任何有问题的设备
only has a finite amount of those things.
只有有限数量的东西。
I only have a finite number of fingers.
我只有有限数量的手指。
Using unary, my old school hashmark approach,
使用一元，我的旧学校hashmark方法，
I can count to five on this hand.
我可以数到五手。
Using binary, I claimed I could count to 31 on this hand.
使用二进制文件，我声称在这方面我可以算到31。
But it's still finite.
但它仍然是有限的。
I cannot count to infinity on this hand because I only have five fingers.
我不能指望这只手上无限，因为我只有五根手指。
Similarly does a computer only have so many transistors or so
类似地，计算机只有这么多晶体管
many bytes or bits of memory, and at some point,
许多字节或内存位，在某些时候，
the programmer has to think about what is he
程序员必须考虑他是什么
or she going to do when the user wants to count so high that you
或者当用户想要数到你的数量时，她会去做
can't physically fit it anymore.
不能再适合它了。
You have to give up like this and say something semi accurately
你必须放弃这样，半准确地说出一些东西
or you have to handle that issue in some other way.
或者您必须以其他方式处理该问题。
And we'll see when we get to C that how you handle this problem is not
我们会在C到达时看到你如何处理这个问题
necessarily straightforward, and indeed a lot of software
必须直截了当，而且确实有很多软件
out there does not handle this problem.
那里没有处理这个问题。
And odds are, all of us have programs that if you
而且，如果你这样，我们所有人都有程序
type big enough words or big enough numbers into them,
输入足够大的单词或足够大的数字，
they might very well break or crash or freeze
他们可能会很好地破坏或崩溃或冻结
because the humans, unlike MIT, did not anticipate that that might actually
因为与麻省理工学院不同，人类并没有预料到这可能是真的
happen and handle it.
发生并处理它。
Well, let me go ahead and do this.
好吧，让我继续这样做吧。
Let me open up this program and see if we can't read the code now.
让我打开这个程序，看看我们现在是否无法读取代码。
This is called Pet Zero and this is a program that simulates petting.
这被称为Pet Zero，这是一个模拟宠物的程序。
So if I click play and don't touch the keyboard,
所以，如果我点击播放并且不要触摸键盘，
nothing seems to be happening, but if I now move my cursor over to the cat--
似乎没有任何事情发生，但如果我现在把光标移到猫身上 -
[MEOW]
[喵]
Aw.
噢。
It's kind of cute.
这有点可爱。
[MEOW]
[喵]
Right now, it's more only meowing on demand when you pet the cat.
现在，当你养宠物时，它更只是喵喵叫。
Why?
为什么？
Well, notice I've added some other building blocks.
好吧，请注意我添加了一些其他构建块。
We haven't used this one before, but it intuitively
我们之前没有使用过这个，但直观地说
probably makes pretty clear sense.
可能很清楚。
When the green flag is clicked, forever do the following.
单击绿色标记时，请永远执行以下操作。
If the cat is touching the mouse pointer-- this thing in blue
如果猫正在触摸鼠标指针 - 这个东西是蓝色的
is what we called earlier a Boolean expression.
我们之前称之为布尔表达式。
It has a yes/no, a true/false, a one/zero answer.
它有一个是/否，一个真/假，一个/零答案。
And touching mouse pointer is one of the options in the little drop
触摸鼠标指针是小滴的选项之一
down here if you tinker with it.
如果你修补它，就在这里。
So if the cat is touching the mouse pointer, then and only then,
所以，如果猫正在触摸鼠标指针，那么只有这样，
play sound meow until done.
发出声音喵喵直到完成。
So we've combined now functions with loops with a condition.
所以我们现在将函数与带有条件的循环结合起来。
But why the loop?
但为什么循环呢？
The cat's only meowing once when I pet him.
当我养宠物时，猫只会喵喵叫一次。
Why am I doing anything forever here?
为什么我在这里永远做什么？
Someone-- yeah.
有人 - 是的
Yeah.
是啊。
I might want to pet it again, so I want the program to anticipate that.
我可能想再次宠爱它，所以我希望程序能够预料到这一点。
And honestly, if I omitted this forever block and my program
老实说，如果我省略了这个永远的块和我的程序
instead looked just like this--
相反看起来像这样 -
so let me get rid of that and this--
所以让我摆脱这个 - 这个 -
and then I clicked play, and now, I hover over him,
然后我点击了播放，现在，我将鼠标悬停在他身上，
why is it not working even once?
为什么它甚至不工作一次？
Say it again.
再说一遍。
Yeah.
是啊。
So I mean, at this point, if I can summarize,
所以我的意思是，在这一点上，如果我能总结一下，
the computer is so damn fast that this already
电脑真是太快了，已经这么快了
happened by the time I moved my cursor over to the cat, and at the moment
当我把光标移到猫身上时，就发生了
I clicked play, I was not touching the cat.
我点击了游戏，我没有碰到那只猫。
Those blocks executed, so to speak, top to bottom.
可以这么说，这些块从上到下执行。
That's it for the program.
这就是该计划。
So by the time I move the cursor over to the cat, the program is over.
因此，当我将光标移动到cat时，程序结束了。
It's not listening.
它不是在听。
And so forever, this way I can actually listen in perpetuity for something
永远这样，我实际上可以永远倾听某些事情
to actually happen.
实际发生。
What if I want to do something not just if something is true,
如果我想要做的事情不仅仅是某些事情是真的，
but handle two cases?
但处理两个案件？
If or else.
如果否则。
Well, let me go ahead and open up Pet One.
那么，让我继续开放Pet One。
And this is another example.
这是另一个例子。
And could someone perhaps describe, after reading this code, what
在读完这段代码之后，有人可能会形容一下
this program is going to do instead?
这个程序会改为吗？
Yeah.
是啊。
Exactly.
究竟。
And let me summarize more verbally.
让我更口头地总结一下。
So if this time, you're touching the cat, it's going to roar instead.
所以，如果这一次，你正在触摸猫，它会发出咆哮声。
Else, it's just going to meow sweetly.
不然，它只是甜蜜地喵喵叫。
So this time, it is meowing perpetually once every second,
所以这一次，它每秒都在喵喵叫一次，
but if you touch this particular cat, it doesn't like it.
但如果你触摸这只特殊的猫，它就不喜欢它了。
So play.
所以玩。
[MEOW]
[喵]
Meow.
喵。
And now.
现在。
[ROAR]
[怒吼]
Don't touch the cat.
别碰猫。
So now, we might interact in two different ways
所以现在，我们可能以两种不同的方式进行互动
by having two different roads that you can go down.
通过两条不同的道路，你可以走下去。
Well, let's actually make something a little more interactive.
好吧，让我们实际上做一些更具互动性的东西。
Let me go ahead and open another example.
让我继续，打开另一个例子。
This one's called Bounce Zero because now, we
这个叫做Bounce Zero，因为现在，我们
can start to see some design elements from what Oscar Time was.
可以从Oscar Time开始看到一些设计元素。
Like this now it's getting a little interesting.
就像这样现在它变得有点有趣了。
What is actually going on here?
这里到底发生了什么？
So let me zoom in on the blocks here.
那么让我放大这里的块。
This block is just saying forever move 10 steps, which
这块只是说永远移动10步，其中
is another block we haven't seen.
是另一个我们没见过的街区。
But 10 steps is like 10 pixels.
但是10个步骤就像是10个像素。
So move 10 pixels on the screen.
所以在屏幕上移动10个像素。
But if you're touching the edge, then turn around 180 degrees.
但是如果你碰到边缘，那么转过180度。
And you can see exactly that happening.
你可以清楚地看到发生的事情。
Scratch is turning around 180 degrees and this rotation style just
Scratch正在转动180度，这种旋转风格正好
means double back.
意味着双背。
Don't like loop around 180 degrees.
不喜欢180度左右的环路。
So that's kind of cool.
所以这很酷。
But this is not how humans or cats walk.
但这不是人类或猫走路的方式。
Like what is obviously unnatural about this?
就像这显然不自然一样？
Yeah.
是啊。
I mean, I mean, I can't even simulate it, right?
我的意思是，我的意思是，我甚至无法模拟它，对吧？
Like his feet are in static position, yet sliding back and forth
就像他的脚处于静止位置，但来回滑动
on the screen.
屏幕上。
And yet, that is not what walking is.
然而，这不是走路的原因。
Like walking presumably has some kind of movement and what?
喜欢走路大概有某种运动​​和什么？
Well, we could just kind of simulate it like--
好吧，我们可以像它一样模拟它 -
OK, I could just walk--
好的，我可以走路 -
walking and you can imagine taking like really quick photographs of my legs
走路，你可以想象我的腿很快拍照
or the cat's leg moving and then just deciding this photo
或猫的腿移动，然后只是决定这张照片
will be representative of one step.
将代表一步。
This photo will be representative another.
这张照片将是另一个代表。
And you know, with just two of those steps,
你知道，只有两个步骤，
I'd wager we could actually do a pretty good job of simulating
我敢打赌，我们实际上可以很好地模拟
what walking looks like.
什么走路看起来像。
In fact, if I go back to where we began, this picture of Scratch,
事实上，如果我回到我们开始的地方，这张图片是Scratch，
what if I just move his legs ever so slightly, then go back,
如果我只是稍微移动他的腿，然后回去，
then go forward?
那么继续前进？
And even just in my PDF, I can simulate animation by hitting up arrow,
即使只是在我的PDF中，我也可以通过点击箭头来模拟动画，
down arrow, up arrow, down arrow because it kind of
向下箭头，向上箭头，向下箭头因为它的种类
looks like he's walking now, when really, your human eyes are just seeing
看起来他现在正在走路，真的，你的人眼刚刚看到
two different pictures again and again.
两个不同的图片一次又一次。
So how can I do this?
那我该怎么做呢？
Well, if I go back to Scratch, he's still walking.
好吧，如果我回到Scratch，他还在走路。
Let me go ahead and open up Bounce One, the second version of this, and now,
让我继续开放Bounce One，这是第二个版本，现在，
do this.
做这个。
OK.
好。
So how did I add this?
那我怎么加这个呢？
There's a little purple block that we haven't seen yet,
还有一个我们还没见过的紫色块，
but if you poke around the categories, you'll
但是，如果你围绕这些类别，你会
see other blocks like this next costume that just keeps
看到像这样的其他街区下一个刚刚保留的服装
changing the costume that he's wearing.
改变他穿的服装。
It turns out Scratch exists as a picture and his default picture
事实证明，Scratch作为图片和他的默认图片存在
is him not moving, but if I go up here to top left and click costumes,
他没有动，但如果我上到左上角点击服装，
you can actually see that here's his one costume.
你真的可以看到这是他的一件服装。
Here's his second costume.
这是他的第二套服装。
And so that purple block that says next costume, because it's
所以紫色的块说下一件服装，因为它是
in the forever loop, it just keeps doing next, next, next, next, next, just
在永远的循环中，它只是继续做下一个，下一个，下一个，下一个，下一个，只是
showing one costume or the other.
显示一件服装或另一件。
They're clearly mimicking walking.
他们显然模仿行走。
Now, this is not very unnatural.
现在，这不是很不自然。
Why don't we slow him down to, say, five steps at a time and have him go again?
我们为什么不慢慢将他放慢速度，比如一步五步，让他再去？
Now, this is still going pretty fast.
现在，这仍然很快。
Let me go ahead and say--
让我继续说 -
we could have control.
我们可以控制。
We could have him wait a second after moving very dramatically.
我们可以让他在非常戏剧性地移动后等待一秒钟。
We could probably speed this up.
我们可以加快速度。
So let's wait 1/10 of a second, 0.1.
让我们等待1/10秒，0.1。
Or maybe let's do 0.01, 1/100 of a second.
或者让我们做0.01,1 / 100秒。
Now, it's getting a little more realistic.
现在，它变得更加现实了。
But this is what animation is.
但这就是动画。
If you've ever watched a cartoon or a movie based on pictures like this,
如果你曾经看过基于这样的照片的卡通片或电影，
you're just tinkering with some of these parameters, these inputs,
你只是修补一些这些参数，这些输入，
in order to produce this output by understanding
为了通过理解产生这个输出
what the fundamental representation of these things is, which in this case
在这种情况下，这些东西的基本表现是什么
are just pictures, again and again and again in order
只是图片，一次又一次的顺序
to create that animation.
创建该动画。
But what about interactivity?
但是交互性怎么样？
Let me do this one myself.
让我自己做这个。
Let me go ahead and get rid of this, go back to events, and say,
让我继续，摆脱这个，回到事件，然后说，
when green flag clicked.
点击绿旗时。
Then, let me go ahead and grab a forever block
然后，让我继续前进，抓住永远的阻挡
so that this keeps going again and again.
所以这一直在继续。
And then, let me go ahead to go to motion.
然后，让我继续讨论动议。
It turns out that under motion, there's this block we haven't seen--
事实证明，在运动中，我们还没有看到这个区块 -
point towards the mouse pointer.
指向鼠标指针。
And let me go ahead and pull this in here.
让我继续前进，把它拉到这里。
And then, let me have it move just like one step at a time, instead of 10.
然后，让我让它一步一步地移动，而不是10步。
What is this going to do?
这是怎么回事？
What's this program do?
这个程序做什么用的？
Yeah.
是啊。
Say it again.
再说一遍。
Follow the mouse.
跟着鼠标。
Yeah.
是啊。
This is kind of like a way of taking your cat for a walk.
这有点像带你的猫散步的方式。
Perhaps not quite the animal we intended, but he'll follow the cursor.
也许不是我们想要的动物，但他会按照光标。
And I can actually speed this up a little bit.
而我实际上可以加快这一点。
So let's have him move 10 steps.
让我们让他迈出10步。
OK.
好。
Now, there we go.
现在，我们去吧。
So now, he's moving up and down, and so now, it's interactive.
所以现在，他正在上下移动，所以现在，它是互动的。
So you might recall that when we were playing Oscar Time earlier and picking
所以你可能还记得我们早些时候和奥斯卡时间一起玩的时候
up--
up--
OK.
好。
Don't do that.
不要那样做。
See, that's a bug.
看，这是一个错误。
He's just confused.
他只是困惑。
He's constantly moving toward it, but you're already--
他不断走向它，但你已经 -
OK.
好。
So we're going to stop.
所以我们要停下来。
So now, he's following, but that's how we might now create,
现在，他正在关注，但这就是我们现在可能创造的方式，
for instance, the ability to move those pieces of trash
例如，移动那些垃圾的能力
around and have them follow the mouse cursor.
周围，​​让他们按照鼠标光标。
If you think back to Oscar Time, every time you picked up a piece of trash,
如果你回想奥斯卡时间，每次你拿起一块垃圾，
he'd follow the cursor because there was a forever loop and a block like this
他会跟着光标，因为有一个永远的循环和一个像这样的块
pointing toward the mouse pointer.
指向鼠标指针。
Well, now, let's integrate multiple ideas
那么，现在，让我们整合多个想法
and actually have multiple scripts.
实际上有多个脚本。
I proposed earlier that programs can actually have multiple threads.
我之前提出过，程序实际上可以有多个线程。
A thread is just a fancy way of saying, in our context, multiple scripts.
在我们的上下文中，线程只是一种奇特的方式，可以说多个脚本。
Multiple scripts in one program that are happening essentially in parallel.
一个程序中的多个脚本基本上并行发生。
A computer can effectively do multiple things at a time thanks to threading,
由于线程，计算机可以一次有效地做多件事，
and more on that down the road.
以及更多关于此的信息。
So these are more involved, but let's see
所以这些涉及更多，但让我们看看
if we can-- let's understand first what this program does.
如果我们能 - 让我们先了解这个项目的作用。
Let me go ahead and hit play.
让我继续前进吧。
And this one tends to be a little loud.
而这个往往有点响亮。
[SEA LION BARKING]
[海洋啤酒]
So the sea lion is just barking endlessly, annoyingly.
因此，海狮正在无休止地咆哮，令人讨厌。
So by reading the code, how can I stop him from barking?
所以通过阅读代码，我怎么能阻止他吠叫？
Hit the spacebar.
点击空格键。
All right.
行。
So hit the spacebar.
所以打空格键。
OK.
好。
I could just stop the program, obviously,
我可以停止这个程序，显然，
but this program is still running, technically.
但从技术上讲，这个程序仍在运行。
But why did that work?
但为什么这样做呢？
Well, notice this on the left hand side is the first script.
好吧，请注意左侧是第一个脚本。
When the green flag is clicked, set this variable that I called muted to false.
单击绿色标志时，将我调用的此变量设置为false。
Could have called it x or y or z or counter, but none of those
可以称之为x或y或z或计数器，但不是这些
really make sense, so I called it muted.
真有意义，所以我把它称为静音。
And I set it equal to false, which is, again, a Boolean value.
我将它设置为等于false，这又是一个布尔值。
True or false just mean yes or no.
是或否只是表示是或否。
Forever, if the keyspace is pressed, then do this.
永远，如果按下键空间，那么执行此操作。
If muted is currently false, then change muted to true.
如果muted当前为false，则将muted更改为true。
Else, change muted to false.
否则，将静音改为假。
So if muted is false, change it to true.
因此，如果muted为false，则将其更改为true。
If muted is true, change it to false.
如果muted为true，则将其更改为false。
Any time the human hits the spacebar, update that variable.
只要人类击中空格键，就更新该变量。
Now, if we look at the other script, which is also driving the sea lion,
现在，如果我们看看另一个也在驱动海狮的剧本，
what is he doing?
他在做什么？
Forever, if muted is false.
永远，如果静音是假的。
So if he's not muted.
所以，如果他不沉默。
If muted is false means not muted.
如果静音是假的意味着没有静音。
Start the sound sea lion and then think hi, hi, hi for two seconds,
启动声音海狮然后想想你好，嗨，嗨两秒钟，
and then wait for one more second.
然后再等一秒钟。
And then just repeat, repeat, repeat.
然后重复，重复，重复。
But if I change with the spacebar muted to true,
但如果我改变空格键静音为真，
he's going to say if muted equals false, that's not so.
他会说，如果静音等于假，那不是这样。
I'm not going to play a sound this time.
这次我不会发出声音。
And so now, we have the ability to integrate multiple scripts together
现在，我们可以将多个脚本集成在一起
in order to achieve a more interactive result.
为了实现更具互动性的结果。
And what about this?
那怎么样？
Back when I was a kid, might have played in the summers Marco Polo.
回到我还是个孩子的时候，可能会在夏天玩马可波罗。
Super simple game.
超级简单的游戏。
We played it in the pool, for some reason, where
我们在游泳池里玩，出于某种原因，在哪里
one person in the pool very safely is blindfolded,
一个人在游泳池里非常安全地被蒙上眼睛，
and then he or she yells Marco.
然后他或她大喊马可。
And then, everyone around him or her is supposed to yell polo.
然后，他或她周围的每个人都应该大喊马球。
And then, the person who's blindfolded is
然后，被蒙住眼睛的人是
supposed to go chase the other kids in the pool and tag them,
应该去追逐池中的其他孩子并标记他们，
and then they become it.
然后他们就成了它。
But in other words, it's this like signaling mechanism.
但换句话说，就像信号机制一样。
Someone yells, Marco and everyone else responds
有人大叫，马可和其他所有人都回应
to that broadcast of the word Marco.
那个广播的单词Marco。
Well, it turns out we can simulate this with these two puppets.
好吧，事实证明我们可以用这两个木偶模拟这个。
This guy here-- notice that I've highlighted the orange puppet
这个人在这里 - 注意到我突出了橙色木偶
because there's a second blue puppet there.
因为那里有第二个蓝傀儡。
Separate sprites.
分开的精灵。
And these are just photographs we uploaded to the game.
这些只是我们上传到游戏中的照片。
Forever, if the key space is pressed, so if the spacebar is pressed,
永远，如果按下键空间，那么如果按下空格键，
say Marco for two seconds and then broadcast an event.
说马可两秒钟，然后播出一个事件。
Meanwhile, the blue puppet here has a super simple block,
同时，这里的蓝色木偶有一个超级简单的块，
but it's fundamentally different from the ones we've seen.
但它与我们看到的根本不同。
He's not starting when the green flag is clicked.
单击绿色标记时，他没有启动。
He is starting only when he receives an event.
他只有在收到一个活动时才会开始。
So it turns out that sprites and Scratch can't hear or see
事实证明，精灵和Scratch听不到或看不到
what the other one is saying in those speech bubbles.
另一个人在那些讲话泡泡中说的是什么。
You have to use a fancier technique, which
你必须使用更高级的技术
is the special block called broadcast, which
是一个叫做广播的特殊块，它
is like passing a note digitally from one sprite to another
就像把一个音符从一个精灵传递到另一个精灵
that the other one can read or receive, so to speak.
另一个人可以阅读或接收，可以这么说。
So only when he receives this event, so to speak,
所以只有当他收到这个事件时，可以这么说
does he say polo for two seconds.
他说马球两秒钟了吗？
And again, the orange puppet sends that secret message
再一次，橙色木偶发送了这个秘密信息
just using this other puzzle piece.
只是使用这个其他拼图。
Broadcast an event, like passing a note that the human doesn't actually see.
广播一个事件，就像传递人类实际上看不到的音符一样。
So if I now hit the green flag and hit the spacebar, orange yells Marco.
因此，如果我现在击中绿旗并击中空格键，橙色会叫马可。
Blue guy yells polo in response.
蓝色的家伙大喊大叫马球。
But those aren't timed together.
但那些没有定时在一起。
Rather, the blue guy is hearing with the orange one has said,
相反，蓝色的家伙正在听到橙色的人说，
thereby allowing multiple sprites to actually intercommunicate.
从而允许多个精灵实际上相互通信。
So how did we get here?
那我们怎么到这里来的？
Well, recall that we had all of these building blocks a moment ago.
好吧，回想一下，我们刚才拥有所有这些构件。
First, we started out with just functions and conditions
首先，我们从功能和条件开始
and Boolean expressions and loops.
和布尔表达式和循环。
We've now added to that the ability to store information
我们现在已经添加了存储信息的能力
in variables and threads to do multiple things at once, and then, if you do
在变量和线程中一次做多个事情，然后，如果你这样做
have multiple things happening, events, where
有多件事情发生，事件，在哪里
they can enter communicate somehow.
他们可以以某种方式进入沟通。
Yet another building block.
又一个构建块。
So if we now take a step back and consider
所以如果我们现在退一步考虑一下
how we can make functions of our own, we have the final piece
我们如何能够发挥自己的作用，我们有最后一块
of the puzzle, so to speak.
可以这么说，这个谜题。
Let me go ahead and do this.
让我继续这样做。
Let me go ahead and create a simple program with, when green flag clipped,
让我继续创建一个简单的程序，当绿色标记被剪切时，
that simply simulates coughing for a cat.
这简单地模拟了猫的咳嗽。
So this cat is going to say not hello, but cough for one second.
所以这只猫会说不是你好，而是咳嗽一秒钟。
And then he's going to go ahead and wait for one second.
然后他会继续等待一秒钟。
And then I'm going to go ahead and copy paste, as I did before--
然后我会像往常一样继续复制粘贴 -
this is one of those do as I say, not as I do-- to implement this program here,
正如我所说的那样，这不是我做的其中之一 - 在这里实施这个程序，
where he coughs three times.
他咳​​嗽了三次。
We already know, though, from earlier that this is not good design.
不过，我们早些时候已经知道这不是好设计。
Why?
为什么？
You're repeating yourself.
你在重复自己。
Don't repeat yourself.
不要重复自己。
DRY is an acronym, actually.
实际上，DRY是一个缩写。
Don't repeat yourself because you're doing
不要重复自己，因为你正在做
three times as many times something that you only really need to do once.
你只需要做一次的事情的三倍。
The solution before, of course, was just use a loop of some sort.
当然，之前的解决方案只是使用某种循环。
So let me actually take that out.
所以让我实际上把它拿出来。
Let me use a repeat block, change 10 to three,
让我使用重复块，将10改为3，
and then just use two of these blocks.
然后只使用其中两个块。
And notice already, the program is so much more compact.
并且已经注意到，该程序非常紧凑。
And now, if I want to change the three to a 30 or to a 10 or any number,
而现在，如果我想将三者更改为30或10或任何数字，
I just change one simple value.
我只是改变一个简单的值。
I don't have to rewrite or copy paste or delete things.
我不必重写或复制粘贴或删除东西。
I can update the program much more readily,
我可以更容易地更新程序，
and now, the same thing is going to happen with just cough, cough, cough.
现在，咳嗽，咳嗽，咳嗽也会发生同样的事情。
But it turns out that it would be nice to henceforth abstract away from this,
但事实证明，从此开始抽象将是很好的，
right?
对？
I just want any program I write to know how to cough.
我只想要我写的任何程序都知道如何咳嗽。
And coughing is really just saying something, perhaps
咳嗽真的只是在说些什么
some number of times.
好几次。
But it turns out we can abstract this away in code.
但事实证明我们可以在代码中抽象出来。
Let me go down to my blocks here and this allows
让我来到我的街区，这允许
me to click this button-- make a block.
我点击这个按钮 - 制作一个块。
It allows me to make my own function.
它允许我自己创造功能。
I get this dialog window here.
我在这里得到这个对话窗口。
And I'm just going to call this block cough.
而我只是称这块阻止咳嗽。
I'm going to go ahead and click OK.
我要继续，然后单击“确定”。
And now, I have this new pink block that itself can have blocks underneath it.
现在，我有了这个新的粉红色块，它本身可以有块。
And you know what I'm going to do?
你知道我要做什么吗？
I'm going to go ahead and do this.
我要继续这样做。
I'm going to go ahead and say cough under there.
我要继续在那里说咳嗽。
And now, notice on the left, I now have access to this new pink piece.
而现在，请注意左侧，我现在可以访问这个新的粉红色。
I can now put this in here.
我现在可以把它放在这里。
So now, notice even though, yes, this is how coughing is implemented
所以现在，请注意，是的，这就是咳嗽的实施方式
on the left hand side here, next time, when I write a program,
在左边这边，下次，当我写一个程序时，
I just want to call cough.
我只想打电话给咳嗽。
And I don't care about those lower level implementation details.
而且我不关心那些较低级别的实现细节。
I don't care about the party or any of that.
我不关心党或其中任何一方。
I just want this to be an abstraction.
我只是希望这是一个抽象。
But I could do better than this wouldn't it
但我可以做得比这更好
be nice if instead of just repeating cough three times,
如果不是只重复咳嗽三次，那就好了，
what if I made that a feature of cough?
如果我做了咳嗽的特征怎么办？
So let me do this.
所以让我这样做。
I can go ahead and right click on this pink piece and I can edit it.
我可以继续并右键点击这个粉红色的部分，我可以编辑它。
That brings up that same window from before.
这会带来前面的那个窗口。
And notice this.
请注意这一点。
Add an input.
添加输入。
So when I make a custom block, I can actually make pretty fancy blocks
因此，当我制作一个自定义块时，我实际上可以制作非常精美的块
just like the ones MIT gives us with the software,
就像麻省理工学院给我们的软件一样，
and now, I can type in something like n.
现在，我可以输入类似n的东西。
And if I add a label just to make it more descriptive, I can just say times.
如果我添加一个标签只是为了使它更具描述性，我可以说时间。
So now, I've made a special custom puzzle
所以现在，我做了一个特殊的定制拼图
piece that says cough some number of times, where n for number
咳嗽很多次，其中n为数字
is just the go to variable that programmers tend to use.
只是程序员倾向于使用的变量。
So now, I can actually move this repeat block into cough itself,
所以现在，我实际上可以将这个重复块移动到咳嗽本身，
but rather than hard code 3, notice this.
但不是硬代码3，请注意这一点。
I can steal that variable and now say cough this many times by repeating
我可以偷走那个变量，现在通过重复多次咳嗽
saying this again and again and again.
一次又一次地说这个。
And now, when I cough in my actual program, I just type in three here.
而现在，当我在实际节目中咳嗽时，我只在这里输入三个。
So I have this beautiful abstraction now, so to speak.
所以我现在有了这个美丽的抽象，可以这么说。
Cough this many times and I and no one else in the world
咳嗽这么多次，我和世界上没有其他人
never again needs to care about what it means to cough because we've already
再也不需要关心咳嗽意味着什么，因为我们已经有了
implemented that before.
以前实施过。
And so just as MIT has given us so much functionality
正如麻省理工学院为我们提供了如此多的功能
that we ourselves don't have to think about, so can
我们自己不必考虑，也可以
I now make functionality that I don't have to think about.
我现在做的功能我没有必要考虑。
And as we progress to higher level languages like C and JavaScript
随着我们进步到更高级别的语言，如C和JavaScript
and Python, we're going to continue this process, sometimes
和Python一样，我们有时会继续这个过程
solving problems ourselves by making our own custom puzzle pieces,
通过制作我们自己的定制拼图来解决问题，
but very often using things called libraries,
但经常使用称为库的东西，
code that other humans wrote before us that's just useful to get the job done,
其他人在我们面前写的代码对于完成工作非常有用，
just as Scratch has done here in part for us.
就像Scratch在这里为我们做的一样。
Let me go ahead, then, and bring all of this
那么，让我继续，并带来所有这一切
together by opening this other example here.
在这里打开另一个例子。
Let me go ahead and open up this one, which isn't something we've seen,
让我继续开放这个，这不是我们见过的，
but it's kind of an interactive game like this made by a former student.
但这是一个由前学生制作的像这样的互动游戏。
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
Should we have an apple?
我们应该有苹果吗？
Yes.
是。
A little animation.
一点点动画。
OK.
好。
That didn't end well.
那并没有结束。
Let's try again.
让我们再试一次。
Play again.
再玩一次。
And notice the say block is happening.
并注意说块正在发生。
There's some kind of ask block.
有某种问题阻止。
The student was checking if the human typed in yes or no.
学生正在检查是否输入了是或否。
Let's type no this time.
我们这次不打字。
No apple.
没有苹果。
Ooh.
哦。
Cupcake.
蛋糕。
OK.
好。
Yes.
是。
Enter.
输入。
OK.
好。
Don't do that.
不要那样做。
One more life.
再过一次生命。
Here we go.
开始了。
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
OK.
好。
No apple.
没有苹果。
No cupcake.
没有蛋糕。
Little variable.
变数不大。
[SCREAMING]
[尖叫]
[LAUGHTER]
[笑声]
OK.
好。
So I won the game.
所以我赢了比赛。
In our final moments here, let me go ahead and open one final example.
在这里的最后时刻，让我继续前进，打开最后一个例子。
As you know, CS50 is offered not only at Harvard, but at Yale, as well,
如您所知，CS50不仅在哈佛大学提供，而且在耶鲁大学也提供，
so it seems fitting to perhaps end on a note that
因此，似乎最终可能以一张纸条结束
pits one campus perhaps against the other by way of another game
通过另一场比赛可能会让一个校园对阵另一个校园
that a former student wrote called Ivy's Hardest Game.
一位前学生写的名为Ivy的最难的游戏。
But for this, I think we need one final volunteer who's company coming up.
但对于这一点，我认为我们需要一个最终的志愿者，他的公司即将到来。
OK.
好。
First hand.
第一手资料。
Right there.
在那里。
Come on down.
下来吧。
So in Ivy's Hardest Game, it's a game played with the keyboard.
因此，在常春藤最难的游戏中，这是一个用键盘玩的游戏。
And even though it might look a little overwhelming at first glance,
即使乍一看它看起来有点压倒性，
just like Oscar Time did and just like the gingerbread animation might,
就像奥斯卡时代一样，就像姜饼动画一样，
realize that if you decompose it in just your mind's eye thinking about what
意识到如果你只是在思考什么的时候分解它
those individual building blocks are, you can probably
那些单独的构建块，你可能
guess what the puzzle pieces are.
猜猜拼图是什么。
Hi.
你好。
What's your name?
你叫什么名字？
ANDREA: Hi.
安德烈：嗨。
I'm Andrea.
我是安德烈。
DAVID MALAN: Andrea.
大卫马兰：安德烈。
David.
大卫。
Nice to meet you.
很高兴见到你。
Here is Ivy's Hardest Game.
这是常春藤最难的游戏。
Pits you against all of the Ivies here.
让你对抗所有的常春藤。
And then right after this will we adjourn for cupcakes in the transept.
然后就在这之后我们会在transept中休息吃蛋糕。
Ready?
准备？
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[音乐播放]
[MUSIC - MC HAMMER, "U CAN'T TOUCH THIS"]
[音乐 -  MC HAMMER，“你不能接触到这个”]
MC HAMMER: (SINGING) You can't touch this.
MC HAMMER :(唱歌）你不能碰这个。
DAVID MALAN: Nice.
大卫马兰：很好。
[MUSIC - MC HAMMER, "U CAN'T TOUCH THIS"]
[音乐 -  MC HAMMER，“你不能接触到这个”]
MC HAMMER: (SINGING) You can't touch this.
MC HAMMER :(唱歌）你不能碰这个。
My, my, my, my.
我的，我的，我的。
Music hits you so hard.
音乐很难打动你。
Makes me say, oh my lord.
让我说，哦，我的主人。
Thank you for blessing me with a mind to rhyme and two hype feet.
谢谢你用韵达和两个炒作的脚来祝福我。
It feels good when you know you're down.
当你知道自己失败时感觉很好。
A super dope homeboy from the Oaktown.
来自Oaktown的超级涂料男生。
And I'm known as such.
我就是这么认识的。
And this is the beat you can't touch.
这是你无法触及的节拍。
I told you, homeboy, you can't touch this.
我告诉过你，顺道，你不能碰这个。
Yeah.
是啊。
That's how we're living and you know you can't touch this.
这就是我们的生活方式，你知道你无法触及这一点。
Look in my eyes.
看我的眼睛。
Man, you can't touch this.
伙计，你不能碰这个。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
[MUSIC - MC HAMMER, "U CAN'T TOUCH THIS"]
[音乐 -  MC HAMMER，“你不能接触到这个”]
(SINGING) Fresh new kicks and pants.
（唱歌）新鲜的新踢和裤子。
You got it like that and now you know you want to dance.
你得到它，现在你知道你想跳舞。
So move out of your seat and get a fly girl
因此，离开你的座位，让一个飞行的女孩
and catch this beat while it's rolling.
在它滚动的时候抓住这个节拍。
Hold on.
坚持，稍等。
Pump a little bit and let me know it's going on like that.
抽一点，让我知道它正在发生这样的事情。
Like that.
像那样。
Cold on a mission so pull on back.
任务冷，所以拉回来。
Let them know that you're too much and this is the beat you can't touch.
让他们知道你太多了，这是你无法触及的节拍。
Yo, I told you, you can't touch this.
哟，我告诉过你，你不能碰这个。
Why you standing there, man?
为什么你站在那里，伙计？
You can't touch this.
你不能碰这个。
Yo, sound the bells.
哟，响起了钟声。
School is in, sucker.
学校在，傻逼。
You can't touch this.
你不能碰这个。
Give me a song or rhythm.
给我一首歌或节奏。
Making them sweat.
让他们流汗。
That's what I'm giving them.
这就是我给他们的东西。
Now they know when you talk about the Hammer,
现在他们知道你什么时候谈论锤子，
you talking about a show that's hyped and tight.
你在谈论一个被大肆宣传的节目。
Singers are sweating so pass them a wipe or a tape
歌手正在出汗，所以要擦拭或擦拭
to learn what it's going to take in the 90s to burn the charts.
了解90年代烧制图表需要采取的措施。
DAVID MALAN: Second to last level.
大卫马兰：倒数第二。
[MUSIC - MC HAMMER, "U CAN'T TOUCH THIS"]
[音乐 -  MC HAMMER，“你不能接触到这个”]
MC HAMMER: (SINGING) Either work hard or you might as well quit.
MC HAMMER :(唱歌）要么努力工作，要么你也可以退出。
That's word because you know you can't touch this.
这句话是因为你知道你无法触及这一点。
You can't touch this.
你不能碰这个。
Break it down.
分解。
Stop.
停止。
Hammer time.
锤击时间。
Go with the flow, it is said.
据说，顺其自然。
If you can't groove to this, then you probably are dead.
如果你不能这样做，那么你可能已经死了。
So wave your hands in the air.
所以挥挥手在空中。
Bust a few moves.
匆匆几步。
Run your fingers through your hair.
用手指梳理头发。
This is it for a winner.
这是赢家。
Dance to this and you're going to get thinner.
跳舞到这个，你会变得更瘦。
Move.
移动。
Slide your rump.
滑你的臀部。
Just for a minute, let's all do the bump, bump, bump.
只是一分钟，让我们所有人做碰撞，碰撞，碰撞。
Yeah.
是啊。
You can't touch this.
你不能碰这个。
Look, man.
看，伙计。
You better get hype, boy, because you know--
你最好得到炒作，男孩，因为你知道 -
[CROWD YELLING]
[CROWD YELLING]
[MUSIC - MC HAMMER, "U CAN'T TOUCH THIS"]
[音乐 -  MC HAMMER，“你不能接触到这个”]
(SINGING) Break it down.
（唱歌）分解。
DAVID MALAN: [INAUDIBLE]
大卫马兰：[听不清]
ANDREA: [INAUDIBLE]
安德烈：[听不清]
DAVID MALAN: No.
大卫马兰：没有。
It's OK.
没关系。
[MUSIC - MC HAMMER, "U CAN'T TOUCH THIS"]
[音乐 -  MC HAMMER，“你不能接触到这个”]
One more life.
再过一次生命。
[MUSIC - MC HAMMER, "U CAN'T TOUCH THIS"]
MC HAMMER :(唱歌）停止。
Hammer time.
锤击时间。
DAVID MALAN: All right.
大卫马兰：好的。
A round of applause for Andrea, if we could.
如果可能的话，为安德里亚赢得一片掌声。
[APPLAUSE]
[掌声]
OK.
好。
That's it for CS50.
这就是CS50。
See the website for details.
有关详细信息，请访问网站
We'll see you for cake in the transept.
我们会在转录中看到你的蛋糕。
Welcome aboard.
欢迎乘坐。